เราจะไปลงรายละเอียดเชิงลึกกัน
โดยฉันจะแสดงให้เห็นถึงเบื้องหลัง
เจาะลึกเข้าไปในส่วนลึกของ parachains
ดังนั้นเราจะพูดถึง
การอนุมัติการตรวจสอบ
parachains ทำงานอย่างไร
สิ่งที่ยากที่สุดเกี่ยวกับ
parachains
และกับระบบ blockchain ทุกประเภท ๆ
คือ
คุณรู้ว่านี่เป็นปัญหา
ที่แท้จริงที่ว่าคุณ
จะรักษาความปลอดภัยได้อย่างไร
เหนือชาร์ดที่แตกต่างกันทั้งหมดโดยที่ทุกคนไม่ได้ตรวจสอบ
ทุกอย่างโดยที่ตัวตรวจสอบความถูกต้อง
ไม่ได้ตรวจสอบพาราเชนทั้งหมด
เพราะเมื่อ คุณจะไม่ปรับขนาดให้เหมาะสม
คุณรู้ว่าคุณแค่ใช้งานโหนดเต็ม 100
โหนดบนคอมพิวเตอร์
นั่นไม่ใช่สิ่งที่เราต้องการ
เรามีโปรโตคอลทั้งหมด
ที่เรียกว่าการตรวจสอบการอนุมัติ
ฉันจะเข้าเนื้อหาที่ละน้อย
จากนั้นฉันจะแสดงตัวอย่าง
การทำงาน
บนเครือข่ายทดสอบในเครื่อง
ดังนั้นฉันจึงจะ pull request
ตอนนี้มันถูกรวมเข้าด้วยกันแล้ว
มันมีโค้ดเยอะมาก ประมาณ 7,000 บรรทัด
ฉันไม่รู้ ฉันเห็น
สิ่งที่ฉันเห็นบนหน้าจอของฉัน
เป็นรูปสี่เหลี่ยมผืนผ้าสีเทาที่มุมบนขวา
ปิดส่วนหนึ่งของสไลด์ของฉัน
ฉันไม่แน่ใจ คุณเห็นมันไหม
มันไม่ควรอยู่ที่นั่น
ฉันคิดว่านั่นเป็นข้อผิดพลาด
ของการแชร์หน้าจอ
ฉันคิดว่าฉันเห็นสีเทารอบๆ โอเค
ด้านบนขวา ดี ฉันไม่รู้ว่า
ฉันรู้วิธีเขียนโค้ด parachains
ฉันไม่รู้วิธีแก้ สี่เหลี่ยมผืนผ้า นี้ออกยังไง
อดทนกับฉันหน่อย
อืม เรามีโค้ดประมาณ 7,000 บรรทัดที่นี่
เราเพิ่มเข้าไป คุณรู้มากกว่านั้น
เกี่ยวกับการทดสอบและสิ่งต่างๆ แต่คุณรู้ว่า
มีโค้ดจำนวนมาก
คุณจะเห็น pink bleeding
wojack action
หากคุณกำลังพยายามอ่านโค้ดนี้
มันจะเป็น
ให้เจาะลึกลงไปเยอะ ดังนั้นฉันจึงทำสไลด์นำเสนอนี้
ในขั้นต้นเพื่อเรียงลำดับ
ว่าคุณสมบัติหลักของโค้ดนี้คืออะไร
โดยที่ไม่
ใส่โค้ดทั้งหมดด้วยตัวมันเอง
ทำไมมันถึงเดินหน้าไปได้มาก
เรามาถอยกลับกันไปที่เป้าหมายของเรา
คือการสร้างความมั่นคงทางเศรษฐกิจสำหรับ
polkadot พาราเชนส์
เรามีแนวคิดเรื่อง
ความมั่นคงทางเศรษฐกิจ ซึ่งฉัน
ไม่รู้จริงๆ ว่าทำไมมันถึง
แสดงแค่บางส่วนของสไลด์สุดท้าย
ที่อยู่ตรงกลาง
ของสไลด์ปัจจุบัน เป้าหมายของเราคือ
สร้างความมั่นคงทางเศรษฐกิจสำหรับ parachains
นั่นคือ อืม ทรัพย์สินของคุณ
ทำให้แน่ใจว่าเราสามารถ
ระบุได้ว่าผู้ตรวจสอบความถูกต้อง
คนใดประพฤติตัวมุ่งร้ายและ จัดการมัน เพราะ
เมื่อคุณอยู่ในระบบการ stake
ฉันแน่ใจว่าพวกคุณหลายคนกำลังทำการ stake อยู่
คุณรู้ว่าถ้าผู้ตรวจสอบความถูกต้อง
คุณกำลังเสนอชื่อหรือ ถ้าคุณเป็น
validator
ที่ทำตัวไม่ถูกต้อง คุณกำลังจะ
จัดการ
ดังนั้นมันจึงใช้ validators เพียงไม่กี่ตัว
ในการเอา parachain block ไปที่
relay chain
แต่เราสนใจที่จะ slashing
parachain block
ผู้สนับสนุนของบล็อก Parachain
เหล่านั้นเมื่อบล็อก Parachain
เหล่านั้นไม่ได้ถูกกล่าวถึง
เพียงใน relay chain แต่สิ่งที่เราจะ
เรียก
พร้อมใช้งาน ดังนั้นหลังจากที่พวกเขาได้แจกจ่าย
ข้อมูลไปยังเครื่องมือตรวจสอบความถูกต้องอื่น ๆ ทั้งหมด เพื่อให้พวกเขา
ามารถตรวจสอบสิ่งเหล่านั้นอีกครั้ง
อืม นี่เป็นเส้นทางคร่าวๆ
ของบล็อก parachain เรามีหลายสิ่งหลายอย่าง
ที่เกิดขึ้นพร้อมกัน ดังนั้น parachains
แต่เรารู้ก่อนว่าคุณมีบล็อก parachain
สีชมพูซึ่ง
ซึ่งได้รับการสนับสนุน แล้วมันก็
ถูกกล่าวถึงใน relay chain จากนั้น
มันก็
พร้อมใช้งาน เพื่อให้ผู้สนับสนุนเริ่มต้นเหล่านั้น
แจกจ่ายข้อมูล
ไปยังตัวตรวจสอบความถูกต้องอื่น ๆ ทั้งหมด
เพื่อให้สามารถกู้คืนข้อมูลได้ในภายหลัง
และคุณรู้หลังจากที่คุณมี
บล็อกสีม่วงในนั้น คุณก็มี
บล็อกสีเขียวด้วย ในนั้น
ฉันจึงใช้ด้านซ้ายของบล็อก relay chain
เพื่อระบุสิ่งที่ได้รับ
การสนับสนุนและไม่ได้กล่าวถึง
และไม่พร้อมใช้งาน จากนั้นทางด้านขวา
ของบล็อกอ้างอิงที่ได้รับการ
สนับสนุนและพร้อมใช้งานเพื่อให้คุณเห็น
เป็นอันดับแรก มันไปที่บล็อกสีม่วง
แล้วก็บล็อกสีเขียว
จากนั้นทั้งคู่ก็อยู่
ทางด้านขวาสุดที่
หัวของเชนนั้น
ฉันอยากจะทบทวนอัลกอริธึม grandpa
เล็กน้อย
วิธีที่grandpaทำงานคือ
มันมีโหนดที่ลงคะแนนเสียง
สิ่งที่พวกเขาคิดว่าเป็นเชนที่ดีที่สุด
คือเชนที่ยาวที่สุดที่
พวกเขาเคยเห็นบ่อยๆ
แล้ว grandpa จะคำนวนหาข้อสรุป
ให้คุณรู้ว่าข้อสรุปที่เป็นฉันทามติเป็นอย่างไร
อะไรคือห่วงโซ่ที่ยาวที่สุด
ที่ทุกคนเห็นด้วย
เหมือนกับ
คำนำหน้าทั่วไปนั้น มันเป็นวิธีที่ฉัน
ชอบอธิบาย ถ้าคุณ
ดูไอเดียของ bitcoin
อืมด้วยหลักฐานการทำงาน bitcoin
หรือหลักฐานการทำงาน ethereum หากคุณเพียงแค่ตัด
บล็อกของ chainออกมา หก หรือสิบ บล็อค
บล็อคของมัน
จะมีสายเดียวกัน
ตราบใดที่คุณเพิกเฉย
ต่อบล็อกล่าสุดเหล่านั้น
แต่สิ่งที่ grandpa ทำคือมันทำให้
เป็นมติที่เป็นเอกฉันท์ เหนือสิ่งอื่นใด
คุณจึงสามารถรับรู้ได้ทันทีเมื่อ
โหนดต่าง ๆ เห็นด้วย
ห่วงโซ่ที่คุณรู้จัก ในส่วนของ
เชนนั้น
พวกมันทั้งหมดมีความเห็นพ้องต้องกัน
ดังนั้นคุณจะเห็นได้ว่าโหนดทั้งสาม
นี้มีความคิดที่แตกต่างกัน
สิ่งที่อยู่ตรงหัวของ
เชน แต่ทั้งหมดตกลงกันในบล็อก a b
และ c เพื่อให้สามารถ
ถือว่าเสร็จสิ้นแล้ว
ดังนั้นนี่คือการแสดงอีกรูปแบบหนึ่ง
ว่าสี่ช่วง บล็อก แรกนี้ได้รับการสรุปทั้งหมดแล้ว
โดยที่แม้ว่าจะมี
บล็อกเชนอื่นๆ หลุดออกมาจากพวกนั้น
สิ่งที่เราพยายามจะทำคือ
ขียนกฎการลงคะแนนเสียงที่กำหนดเอง
สำหรับ grandpa ดังนั้น แนวคิดก็คือ
ไม่เป็นไรถ้าบล็อก Parachain
ที่ไม่ดีเข้าไปในสาขาของสายรีเลย์
แต่มันไม่สามารถเข้าไปใน
สาขาสุดท้ายได้ของห่วงโซ่relay chain ได้ ดังนั้นมันจึงไม่
ได้รับการโหวตภายใน grandpa
ดังนั้นเราจึงมีเชน สุดท้าย เรามี
พื้นที่โหวต บน grandpa ที่ใช้สำหรับการโหวต
บนสิ่งที่มีบนบล็อก parachain
ที่เป็นส่วนดีทั้งหมด แล้วเรา
ก็มีรหัสตรวจสอบการอนุมัติที่
ซึ่งเป็น
พื้นที่ดูเหมือนว่า เราไม่แน่ใจ
ด้วยซ้ำว่าบล็อกของ Parachainที่อ้างอิง
ภายในบล็อก relay chain
เหล่านี้ดีหรือไม่ แต่อาจเป็นเช่นนั้น
นี่คือ
จุดที่มีการตรวจสอบจริงเกิดขึ้น
ทางด้านขวา
ตรงกลางนั้น เหมือนที่เราคิด
เป็นสิ่งที่ดีและเราจะลงคะแนนเพื่อ
ดูว่าคุณรู้ว่าสิ่งที่ได้รับการสรุปแล้ว
ด้านซ้ายสุดคือ
สิ่งที่ได้รับการสรุปแล้ว
นั่นคือกฎการลงคะแนน
ถ้าคุณ กำลังเขียนโค้ด
สำหรับ
กฎการสรุปผลของเราคือการโหวตให้เสร็จสิ้น
สมมติว่าบล็อกนี้
อยู่ตรงกลาง
ก็ต่อเมื่อบล็อก parachain สีเขียวนั้นดี
แต่
ก็ต่อเมื่อบล็อก para chain สีม่วง
นั้นดีเช่นกัน
นั่นคือ อืม
ประเด็นคือคุณ
ไม่อยากโหวตบล็อก
เว้นแต่บล็อกนั้นและทั้งหมดนั้น
ก่อนหน้านั้น
ดีอยู่แล้ว ดังนั้นฉันจะไปได้
ลึกกว่านี้ด้วยสิ่งนี้ แต่ฉันจะ
จะหยุดหลังจากสไลด์
นี้เพื่อสรุปสิ่งที่เรา
พูดคุยเกี่ยวกับการตรวจสอบการอนุมัติ
คือเราต้องการให้เครือข่ายสรุป
เฉพาะบล็อกที่มี
บล็อก Parachain ที่ดีที่เรา
ควบคุมพฤติกรรมที่บันทึกอย่างซื่อสัตย์
แน่นอนเรามี
เรามีข้อสันนิษฐานนี้
ว่าจะมีการโจมตีบน
เครือข่ายมากถึงหนึ่งในสามของโหนดอาจ
กำลังโจมตีเครือข่าย
สิ่งที่เราจะทำคือผลิต
กฎการลงคะแนนที่สร้างพฤติกรรม
การสรุปผลที่เราต้องการในเครือข่าย
ซึ่งเป็นอีกครั้ง
ที่เราทำการต่อบล็อกลูกโซ่รีเลย์ให้เสร็จเท่านั้น
ที่มี
บล็อกพาราเชนที่ดี
ขอสรุปเป็นภาษาอังกฤษ
เราต้องการเลือกบล็อก b เพื่อลงคะแนนให้ a
บล็อกโซ่รีเลย์
ซึ่งจะเป็นห่วงโซ่
ที่ยาวที่สุด ที่เราจะไปหาตัวตั้งตนแรก
ของเชนนั้น ว่า
บล็อกทั้งหมดระหว่างบล็อกสุดท้าย
และ
บล็อกตั้งต้น ที่ดี
parachain ที่ได้รับคัดเลือก
แล้วเราก็โหวตให้จบเรื่องนั้นแต่
นี่เป็นเพียงช่วงสั้นๆ ดังนั้นสิ่งที่ฉัน
จะทำเดี๋ยวนี้
เข้าเทอร์มินัล และฉันมี
บางอย่างกำลังทำงาน
การหกโหนด nevalidators รันบน testnet
สามพาราเชน
ที่เราเห็นจริงๆคือ เอ่อ
validators
รวมถึง parachain
ใน relay chain
อืม มันกำลังใส่พวกนี้ลงใน
relay chain และพวกมันจะ
กระจายข้อมูลที่มีอยู่
แล้วมันก็เลือกตรวจสอบ
บล็อคเหล่านั้นเองแ
การถ่ายทอดงานที่พวกเขา
ที่ได้รับการตรวจสอบแล้ว
การกู้คืนข้อมูล การทำการตรวจสอบ
ตรวจสอบพวกเขาแล้ว
เอ่อ การถ่ายทอดการอนุมัติการโหวต ดังนั้นคุณ
เห็นว่ามีแอคชั่นเยอะที่นี่
เช่น
โหนดบอกว่าโอเคฉันถูกกำหนดให้
ตรวจสอบสิ่งนี้และโหนดอื่น ๆ
บอกว่าโอเค คุณได้รับมอบหมายให้ตรวจสอบ
ดังนั้น ฉันจะไม่ทำมัน
โอเค ถ้าอย่างนั้นพวกเขาตรวจสอบแล้วพวกเขา
ถ่ายทอดงานเพื่อให้มี
กิจกรรมที่วุ่นวายอย่างต่อเนื่อง
กำลังเกิดขึ้น
นั่นคือการจบบล็อก parachain
และสิ่งที่เราเห็น
คือว่า นี้
เป็นตัวแทนของไลค์ซึ่งรีเลย์ เชน
เรา ถือว่ามันดี
เราสามารถเห็นเหมือนภายในหน้าต่าง 50 บล็อกนี้
จาก 312 ถึง 263
บล็อกเหล่านั้นทั้งหมดได้รับ
อนุมัติอย่างเพียงพอ
โดย uh validators คุณจะได้รู้บางครั้ง
คุณจะเห็นเหมือนอันแรกไม่ได้รับ
อนุมัติแต่ได้รับการอนุมัติจริง
ค่อนข้างเร็วและจะ
อาจะถึง สามพาราเชน
บล็อกต่อ relay chain บล็อก ตั้งแต่เราเริ่ม
ทำงานเป็นเครือข่ายสาม parachains
อย่างไรก็ตามนั่นคือ คำอธิบายสั้นๆ
เป็นการนำเสนอ แบบเร็วๆ เกี่ยวกับการอนุมัติ
การตรวจสอบ เอ่อ เป็นหัวข้อที่สนุกที่จะเจาะลึกลงไป
มีข้อมูลมากมาย
มันอยู่ในคู่มือผู้ปฏิบัติ แต่สำหรับ
ฉันจะสรุปมันและส่งมอบให้กับ
สมาชิกชุมชนที่ยอดเยี่ยมของเรา
สวัสดีทุกคน ฉันคือ aiden จาก snowfork
และตามที่อธิบายไว้เรากำลัง สร้าง สะพาน
ระหว่าง polkadot และ ethereum
มีความพิเศษบางอย่างที่น่าสนใจไม่เหมือนใคร
ของลักษณะสะพานของเราในเรื่องนั้น
เป็นการกระจายอำนาจแบบโปร่งแสงอย่างเต็มที่และ
เราบรรลุสิ่งนั้นโดยการทำงานอย่างเต็มที่สำหรับ
ลูกค้าทั้งสองเชน
เอ่อ บน polkadot มีเส้นเหมือน
ethereum และ บนethereum มี
polka dot เพราะมีเส้นสำหรับ
polka dots
อีกประการหนึ่งคือ
จุดประสงค์โดยทั่วไป ดังนั้นฉันจะเริ่มแสดง
เดโม ฉันสามารถแสดงให้คุณดู
เราอยู่จุดไหน และ มัน
ทำงานอย่างไร อย่างแรกที่คุณ
เห็น
ฉันกำลังยุ่งอยู่กับการดู logs relayer ของเรา
relayer
คือ microservice ที่ทำงานตรง
กลางสองตัวที่มีหน้าที่ส่ง
state กลับไปกลับมาระหว่าง
อืม มันไม่น่าเชื่อถือเลย
ใครๆ ก็เรียกใช้ re-layer ได้
โค้ด รีเลย์อาจเป็นอันตรายก็ได้ มัน
สามารถแก้ไขได้และจะไม่
ไม่เป็นผลดีต่อ โปรโตคอล
ในตอนนี้ คุณสามารถเห็นได้ว่ารีเลย์
กำลังจับตาดูบล็อกและส่วนหัวของ ethereum ใหม่และ
นำส่วนหัว
ของ ethereum เหล่านั้น
และส่งต่อไปยังซับสเตรตไปยัง
parachain ของเราและโดยพื้นฐานแล้ว
กับทุกส่วนหัว
parachain
จะทำการตรวจสอบบรรทัดของ proof of work
ในส่วนหัว
พื่อให้แน่ใจว่าเป็นเหมือน
เชนที่ยาวที่สุด บน ethereum
จากนั้นอัปเดตสถานะล่าสุด
บนส่วนหัวของเชนบน ethereum
เรามีกระบวนการที่คล้ายกัน
ในการไปอีกทิศทางหนึ่งที่เราส่ง
การอัปเดต
ของสิ่งที่เกิดขึ้นบน polka dot
elay chain ไปยัง ethereumและ
และรวมเข้ากับ smart contract
ฉันไม่ได้เรียกร้องในวันนี้
แต่เราเกือบจะเสร็จแล้ว
ใช่แล้ว เรามี
ตัวอย่าง Front-End เล็กน้อยที่ฉัน
สามารถแสดงให้คุณเห็นได้
ประการแรก
พวกนี้อยู่ในระหว่างดำเนินการ
ดังนั้นอาจมีปัญหาเล็กน้อย
และ
ตัวอย่างfront-endโดยเฉพาะ
ยังมี ux polish อีกมากที่ต้องทำ
ดังนั้น
ui และ ux ยังไม่ได้รับการฟอร์แมตอย่างสมบูรณ์
แต่อย่าตัดสินเราจากที่
นขั้นต้นเราต้องการเน้นที่
ฟังก์ชันการทำงานให้คุณเห็น
ที่นี่เรามี มีหน้าสาธิต snowbridge ของเรา
คุณสามารถเห็นได้ว่าฉันได้เชื่อมต่อกระเป๋าเงิน ethereum
และกระเป๋าเงิน polka dot ของฉันเชื่อมต่ออยู่ และฉัน
และฉันมี eth และ snow eth
บางอย่างที่ฉันได้รับ
จากการโอนผ่าน
หน้าจอนี้เมื่อคุณรีเฟรชหน้าเพจ
และเปิดขึ้นมา
เป็นสิ่งที่คุณสามารถใช้ส่ง
ethereumของคุณข้ามไปยัง polka dot
ตัวอย่างเช่น ฉันกำลังจะส่ง ether
ไป 5เหรียญ
ซึ่งตั้งใจให้
เพื่อให้ใช้งานง่าย ที่อยู่ของคุณ
จะถูกเติมโดยอัตโนมัติ เพียงแค่
ใช้เมาส์แล้วคลิกปุ่มส่ง
จากนั้น metamask ของคุณจะปรากฏขึ้น
เพื่อฝาก eth ของคุณ
ฉันจะยืนยันและ ส่งธุรกรรมแล้ว
นี้ไม่ได้เชื่อมต่อกับ ropsten
ฉันกำลังใช้งาน
การสแกนหาข้อมูลภายใน แต่ที่นี่ คุณสามารถดู
รายการธุรกรรมและสิ่งที่เกิดขึ้น
สิ่งแรกที่เราทำคือเรา
กำลังรอให้ธุรกรรมได้รับ
การยืนยันบน ethereum
และ เมื่อสิ่งนั้นเกิดขึ้น วงกลมนี้
ควรเป็นสีเขียว และมันไปยังขั้นตอนถัดไป
หลังจากเสร็จแล้ว ขั้นตอนถัดไป คือ
การส่งต่อข้อความไปยัง polkadot
ดังนั้นมันจึงบันทึกบล็อกการประมวลผลของมันและ
ผู้ถ่ายทอดได้รับข้อความที่คุณ
เห็นที่นี่ และมันกำลังส่งข้อความนั้นไปที่
polkadot
และเราได้วงกลมสีเขียว
มันเพิ่งถูกส่งไปที่ pokedot
ถ้าเราไปดูที่ parachain ของเรา
คุณจะเห็นว่าเพิ่งมี
ฉันคิดว่านี่เป็นอีเวนต์ใหม่ของ eth
และ ethereum ถูกสร้างขึ้นบน
บัญชี polka dot ของฉัน
และมันน่าจะเรียบร้อย ดังนั้นเราเพิ่งส่ง
ether ข้ามไป ห้าเหรียญ
ดังนั้นเมื่อฉันรีเฟรช คุณควรเห็นจำนวน snow eth
ของฉันเพิ่มขึ้นห้า และ ethereum
ของฉันต้องการลดลงห้า
เราจะรวมไว้เช่น
การรีเฟรชอัตโนมัติในเวลา
และขณะนี้ eth ลดลงไปที่
92 eth และ
5 ข้ามไป
อยู่บน polka dot
บน parachain ของเราตอนนี้ฉันต้องการส่ง
eth กลับดังนั้นฉันจึงแตะปุ่มนี้
เพื่อทำการส่งกลับ
และฉันสามารถพูดอีกครั้งได้
ฉันต้องการส่ง snow eth กลับ ห้าเหรียญ
ล้วคลิกปุ่มส่งที่นี่
ตอนนี้กระเป๋าเงิน pokedot ของฉันปรากฏขึ้นและ
ฉันจะลงนามในธุรกรรมและ
ส่งผ่านที่ส่งไปแล้วและ
ตอนนี้เรากำลังรอให้มันรวมอยู่ใน
บล็อก polkadot ของเรา ถ้าเราไปดู
ที่ parachain ของเรา
คุณจะเห็นว่ามีการ เผาเหรียญ eth
ดังนั้น
ข้อความจึงเพิ่งถูกเผาและ
รวมไว้ใน parachain ของเรา
front end ควรตรวจพบ
สิ่งนี้ในไม่กี่นาที
และตอนนี้เรารอให้มันได้รับการถ่ายทอด
ไปที่ฝั่ง ethereum
ดังนั้นฉันจะไปดูการถ่ายทอดอีกครั้ง
และนี่ต้องใช้เวลาอีกนิดหน่อย
เพราะกระบวนการของเราในการส่งต่อ
นั้นซับซ้อนกว่าเล็กน้อย
โดยพื้นฐานแล้ว เรามี commitment scheme ที่กำหนดเอง
Parachain ของเราใช้เพื่อสร้าง
ข้อผูกมัดสำหรับ
อความที่ผ่านเข้ามาและอื่น ๆ
บน ethereum เราสามารถตรวจสอบ
ข้อผูกมัดเหล่านี้ได้อย่างมีประสิทธิภาพมากขึ้น
ซึ่งช่วยให้เราประหยัดค่าก๊าซและ
เพิ่มประสิทธิภาพได้ ดังนั้น
ทุกๆ 10 บล็อกบน parachain ของเรา
ภาระผูกพันเหล่านี้จะรวมเข้าด้วยกัน
และส่งผ่าน และที่นี่คุณ
สามารถ
เห็นการถ่ายทอดเพียง
พบข้อผูกมัด
และเกี่ยวข้องกับ ethereum และคุณ
สามารถเห็นได้ว่ามันส่งธุรกรรม
ไปยัง ethereum ด้วยข้อผูกมัดใหม่นี้ ซึ่ง
รวมถึงกลุ่มข้อความจำนวนมาก
และหากเราย้อนกลับไป คุณจะเห็น
ระดับทั้งหมดเป็นสีเขียว
สิ่งดึงดูดใจเสร็จสิ้นแล้ว
ถ้าฉันรีเฟรช คุณจะเห็นว่า
ยอดคงเหลือของฉันกลับไปเป็นเหมือนเดิมแล้ว
มาดูกัน ใช่แล้ว
ตอนนี้ฉันมี 97 ethเหมือนเดิม
และกลับลงมาเป็นสอง บน snow eth
นั่นเป็นเต็มวงจร ของ ethereum
เรามีฟังก์ชันการทำงาน
สำหรับโทเค็น erc20 ด้วยเช่นกัน
นเครื่อง ฉันมีโทเค็นทดสอบที่ตั้งค่า
และพัฒนาที่นี่ ฉันจึงสามารถสาธิต
การส่งโทเค็นทดสอบไปมาได้
มันเป็นกระบวนการที่คล้ายคลึงกันมาก
กับโทเค็น แน่นอนก่อนอื่นคุณต้อง
ได้รับการอนุมัติเพื่อให้คุณสามารถเห็นได้ว่าฉันมี 100
ยอดคงเหลือ
ฉันได้อนุมัติโทเค็น 40
รายการล่วงหน้าแล้วเพื่อให้สาธิตได้ง่ายขึ้น
และเพื่อให้ฉันสามารถใส่จำนวนเงินและส่ง
โทเค็นได้เหมือนเดิมอีกครั้ง
เราจะได้เห็นกระบวนการผ่าน
วงกลมนี้ที่แสดงทุกขั้นตอน
เรากำลังจะเพิ่มลิงก์
ดังนั้นเมื่อใดก็ตามที่คุณคลิกลิงก์ใดลิงก์หนึ่ง
คุณจะได้รับการเชื่อมโยงไปยัง
Block explorer จริง ที่ซึ่งคุณสามารถ
ทบทวนสิ่งต่าง ๆและ
ละจากมุมมองของผู้ใช้
ช่วยให้ผู้ใช้ทราบว่า
เงินของพวกเขาจะไปที่ใด
และจัดการอย่างไร
เพื่อไม่ให้เกิดความไม่แน่นอนจากมุมมองของผู้ใช้
ตอนนี้คุณจะเห็นว่า
erc20 ที่เพิ่งสร้างเสร็จ
และถูกรวมอยู่ใน parachain ของเรา
ดังนั้นถ้าฉันไปและรีเฟรชคุณ
ควรเห็นยอดคงเหลือ erc20 ของฉัน
ลดลงเหลือ 20
ถ้าฉันไปตรงนี้ ใช่ ยอดคงเหลือ erc20
ของฉันเท่านั้น
ดังนั้นมันจึงลดลงจาก 100 เป็น 80
และยอดคงเหลือที่อนุญาตของฉันลดลงจาก 40 เป็น 20
ถ้าฉันย้อนกลับเพื่อส่ง 20
กลับ
แล้วส่งไปลงนามในธุรกรรม
และตอนนี้เรา ต้องรอ
กระบวนการถ่ายทอด commitment scheme
พิเศษทั้งหมดที่ฉันพูดถึงให้เกิดขึ้นอีกครั้ง
ตัวอย่างเช่น ถ้าหลายคนกำลังใช้
ระบบในเวลาเดียวกัน
ข้อความของพวกเขาจะถูก
รวมเข้าด้วยกันเป็นข้อผูกมัดเดียว
สำหรับ
การเพิ่มประสิทธิภาพการลดราคาก๊าซที่ถูกลง
ข้อผูกมัดยังได้รับการตรวจสอบและ
และผ่านกระบวนการตรวจสอบ เรา
ตรวจสอบทั้งสิ่งที่
เกิดขึ้นบน parachain ของเรา
ผ่านข้อผูกมัดที่กำหนดเองของเรา
เช่นเดียวกับ
สิ่งที่เกิดขึ้นบน polka dot relay chain
ผ่านการตรวจสอบ
กระบวนการผลิตบล็อก relay chain ของbig grandpa
เราควรเห็นดข้อผูกมัดใหม่เข้ามา
เล็กน้อย
และถ้าคุณดู Parachain ของเรา
คุณจะเห็นว่าข้อความที่ถูกเผานี้เกิดขึ้น
และผ่านไป
ดังนั้นอาจต้องใช้เวลาอีกสองสามบล็อก
แต่โดยพื้นฐานแล้วใช่ นั่นคือ
กระบวนการทั้งหมด
สำหรับโทเค็น ethereum และ erc20
อีกสิ่งที่น่าสนใจที่จะชี้ให้เห็น
คือ
โปรโตคอล core bridge
อย่างที่คุณเห็นตรงนี้ ฉันเจอมันแล้ว
และมันทำงานสำเร็จ ดังนั้นหากฉันรีเฟรช
ฉันควรกลับไปเป็น 40 ขอโทษด้วย 200 โทเค็น
นั้นแหละ
สิ่งที่น่าสนใจสุดท้าย
ที่จะพูดถึง
คือแอปพลิเคชั่นที่เราพัฒนาขึ้นนี้
เป็นเพียงตัวอย่างสำหรับส่งโทเค็น
eth และ erc20 ไปมา
แต่จริงๆ แล้วสำหรับทั้งบริดจ์และ
รีเลย์ และโครงสร้างพื้นฐานทั้งหมด
ของเราที่พวกเขาไม่รู้เกี่ยวกับทรัพย์สิน
พวกเขาไม่รู้อะไรเกี่ยวกับโทเค็น
มันถูกใช้งานภายใต้
แอปพลิเคชันด้วยการ
ส่งข้อความโดยพลการอย่างสมบูรณ์
ดังนั้นเราจึงสามารถพัฒนาแอปพลิเคชัน
ข้ามเชน แอปพลิเคชันใด ๆ
ที่ด้านบนของบริดจ์
ไม่จำเป็นต้องทำอะไร
กับการโอนสินทรัพย์
อาจเป็นเพราะ nft, defi
ละคุณจะสามารถส่งข้อความไปมา
สำหรับแอปพลิเคชันประเภทใดก็ได้
แทนที่จะเป็นเพียง
การโอนสินทรัพย์ง่ายๆ
ละ นั่นคือทั้งหมดที่ใช้งานได้จริงในวันนี้
เราไม่มีตัวอย่างส่วนหน้าที่ดี
เกี่ยวกับ
ไม่ใช่การโอนสินทรัพย์พิเศษใดๆ
แต่เราวางแผนที่จะทำในครั้งต่อไป
นี่คือการสิ้นสุดการสาธิตของฉัน
เฮ้ ฉันคืออเล็กซี่ ฉันอยู่ที่นี่ ร่วมกับ ดอม
เราเป็นผู้ร่วมก่อตั้งสองคนของ interlay
และเรากำลังสร้าง polkabtc เพื่อนำ
bitcoin มาสู่ระบบนิเวศ
คือโครงการที่ได้รับทุนจากทั้งสาม
มูลนิธิ และเรากำลังทำงาน
อย่างใกล้ชิดกับ op3 และความเท่าเทียมกัน
เพื่อทำให้สิ่งนี้ เป็นไปได้
polkabtc คืออะไร
polkabtc คือสะพาน btc-polkadot แบบ trustless และ กระจายอำนาจ
ที่สร้างขึ้นโดยใช้
เฟรมเวิร์ก xclaim
เฟรมเวิร์ก xclaim เป็นสิ่ง โดมินิคและ
ฉัน
ออกแบบและดำเนินการ
ในช่วงเวลาของเราที่วิทยาลัย อืม
ตอนนั้นมันเป็นแค่โครงการวิจัยและตอนนี้
เรากำลังนำสิ่งนี้ไปใช้จริงบน
polka dot ดังนั้น polkabtc คืออะไร
polkabtc เป็นสินทรัพย์สำรอง btc หนึ่งต่อหนึ่งบน
polka dot นี่หมายความว่า
ที่คุณล็อค bitcoin บน bitcoin blockchain
และคุณสร้าง polka btc ที่ได้รับการสนับสนุนแบบหนึ่งต่อหนึ่ง
เคล็ดลับส่วนนี้คือ คุณล็อคสิ่งนี้
ด้วยห้องนิรภัยที่มีหลักประกัน
เป็นตัวกลางที่สมบูรณ์
ค้ำประกัน
และทุกคนสามารถมีห้องนิรภัยของตัวเองได้
และตอนนี้เป็นชุดผู้เข้าร่วมที่จำเป็นอย่างยิ่ง
เมื่อคุณมีpolkabtc and polkadot
จากนั้นคุณสามารถย้ายไปยัง parachain ใดก็ได้
และใช้ภายในแอปพลิเคชันใด ๆ ภายใน
ระบบนิเวศโพลก้าดอท
และเมื่อคุณตัดสินใจจะกลับไป คุณก็ทำได้
เพื่อรับ btc ของคุณกลับมาเสมอ
หรือถ้าระบบพัง และทุกอย่าง
พังทลาย
คุณจะยังได้รับเงินคืนเป็นหลักประกันที่
มีอัตราผลประโยชน์ดังนั้นในกรณีที่เลวร้ายที่สุดคุณ
ทำกำไรได้จริง
แล้วทำไมเราถึงบอกว่า polkabtc เป็น
สะพานที่แข็งแกร่งและปลอดภัยที่สุดใน
ระบบนิเวศทั้งหมดไม่เพียงเท่านั้น
polka dot เหตุผลก็คือ
เป็นแบบ trustless และมันมีการกระจายอำนาจ
เพราะคุณสามารถ
แลก polka btc ได้เสมอ
สำหรับ btc หรือคุณจะได้รับเงินคืนเป็น dots
ในอัตราที่เป็นประโยชน์
และมีการกระจายอำนาจเพราะไม่มี
อำนาจกลางตั้งแต่เริ่มต้น มันคือ
กระจายอำนาจตั้งแต่เริ่มต้น
ทุกคนสามารถกลายเป็นห้องนิรภัยเหนือชั้นและ
คุณสามารถเรียกใช้ vault ของคุณเองในฐานะผู้ใช้
ไม่มีข้อจำกัดในการลงทะเบียน
ใครๆ ก็เข้าร่วมได้
มันเปิดอย่างเต็มที่แล้ว สิ่งเดียวที่คุณ
ต้องวางใจเมื่อใช้สะพานนี้
คือ bitcoin ใช้งานได้และ polka dot
ใช้งานได้
แล้วตอนนี้ที่ๆเราอยู่ขณะนี้
เราได้เปิดตัวเบต้าในสัปดาห์นี้และฉัน
แน่นอนว่าพวกคุณส่วนใหญ่เคยได้ยิน
มันทำงานมาสองสามวันและเรา
ยินดีต้อนรับให้คุณได้ทดสอบมันจริงๆ
จะเกิดอะไรขึ้นต่อไปคือเรา
จะได้รับในข้อเสนอแนะที่คุณ
ให้เรา เราจะเสร็จสิ้นการตรวจสอบ
ทำการทดสอบต่อไป และจะทำระบบนี้ต่อไป
ให้แข็งแกร่ง
แล้วไปคุซามะกันต่อดีกว่า
และpolkadotทุกครั้งที่เปิดตัว
มีอะไรใหม่ในเวอร์ชันนี้ตั้งแต่
ครั้งสุดท้ายที่เรานำเสนอและตั้งแต่ alpha
เราได้เปิดตัวห้องนิรภัยและ
เลเยอร์ไคลเอ็นต์ทั้งหมดเป็นโอเพ่นซอร์ส
คุณสามารถดำเนินการได้เลย
เราได้ปรับปรุง ux เต็มรูปแบบแล้ว เราได้รับ 100%
100%
ตอนนี้การสนับสนุนกระเป๋าเงิน bitcoin
สำหรับผู้ใช้งานอัลฟา
เราไม่ได้กลับมาและเรามีการสนับสนุนกระเป๋าเงินที่ จำกัด
ซึ่งหายไปและเรา
รองรับ
กระเป๋าเงิน bitcoin ทั้งหมดรวมถึง
hardware wallet ของ ledger และ trezor ด้วย
เราได้เสร็จสิ้นการตรวจสอบระยะที่สองแล้ว
และเรามีรายละเอียด
และเอกสารใหม่ พร้อมวิดีโอ
ที่แสดงวิธีการใช้ระบบ
ด้านบูรณาการการวิจัยที่เราได้
เปิดตัวโรโคโคโดยที่
เรามี xcmp ทำงานอยู่ และเรา
จริง ๆ แล้วทำงานกับการรวม
ครั้งแรกกับ parachain อื่น ๆ
และเราได้สร้างรูปแบบการสืบทอดคีย์ใหม่
ซึ่งเป็นองค์ประกอบ
ทางเทคนิคที่ทำให้ใช้งานได้จริง
ซึ่งทำให้การใช้งานบนระบบดีขึ้นมาก
ดังนั้นสิ่งต่อไปแน่นอน ux เพิ่มเติม
เรากำลังมองหา
ความคิดเห็นของคุณ
เราจะทำการทดสอบการตรวจสอบเพิ่มเติม และ
จากนั้นตรวจสอบให้แน่ใจว่าเรามี
การกำกับดูแลระบบ
ในด้านการวิจัย ขั้นตอนต่อไปคือ
การผสานรวมกับผลิตภัณฑ์ BTC defi
เราจะเพิ่มการสนับสนุน multi-oracle
และสองสิ่งที่น่าสนใจที่กำลังจะเกิดขึ้นคือ
การ stake อนุพันธ์ที่
ห้องนิรภัยจะสามารถได้รับรางวัลเพิ่มเติม
ภายใต้หลักประกัน
และเรากำลังดำเนินการบน x 2.0 ซึ่งจะทำให้
ระบบมีความปลอดภัยมากขึ้น
และยังลดหลักประกันและ
โดยพื้นฐาน
เมื่อใช้งานได้มันจะ
เป็นการเปลี่ยนแปลงที่ก้าวล้ำในระบบนิเวศ
ของสะพานทั้งหมด
ดังนั้น เมื่อเบต้า ใช้งานได้และโปรด
ตรวจสอบไปที่ beta.polkabtc.io
เพื่อสร้าง polkabtc แรกของคุณ
และฉันยินดีที่จะประกาศว่าคลัง polkadot
จะจัดสรร 1.300 DOT สำหรับผู้ทดสอบเบต้า
เพื่อรับรายได้ ดังนั้นโปรดติดตามเราบน Twitter
เพื่อรับทราบเกี่ยวกับความท้าทายนี้
ฉันจะส่งต่อให้ดอมแล้วนะ
ฉันหวังว่าเขาจะออนไลน์อยู่
เยี่ยมดีมาก
ให้ฉันแชร์หน้าจอแบบเร็วๆ
โอเค ขอบคุณมากสำหรับ
บทนำ alexei แล้วตอนนี้ที่ฉันจะ
แสดงคือเดโม
และนี่ นี่จะเป็น
เดโม่ที่น่าสนใจเพราะ
ฉันกำลังสาธิตโดยตรงในไลฟ์ของเรา
บนระบบเบต้า มันขึ้นอยู่กับว่า
เรามีโหลดอะไรอยู่บ้าง แต่ถ้าคุณ
เข้าชมเว็บไซต์เบต้าของเรา
คุณจะได้รับการต้อนรับโดยทั่วไปด้วยสิ่งนี้
ดังนั้นขณะนี้เรามี
8.1 polkabtc ที่บันทึกและ
และออกมา เรามีบันทึก
หลักประกันมากมาย
หมายเหตุ นี้เป็น dot ปลอม
เพียงเพื่อวัตถุประสงค์ในการทดสอบ
และ bitcoin นั้นไม่ใช่ของจริงเช่นกัน
แต่เรากำลังใช้เครือข่ายทดสอบ bitcoin
และสิ่งที่ฉันจะทำตอนนี้
โดยพื้นฐานแล้วจะนำคุณผ่าน
โฟลว์อย่างรวดเร็ว
ดังนั้นโดยพื้นฐานแล้วสิ่งที่คุณจะทำที่นี่
คือคุณจะป้อนจำนวน polkabtc
ที่คุณต้องการรับและ
คุณได้รับของคุณเองเช่นค่าธรรมเนียมบริดจ์
ที่นี่ยังคงเป็นงานที่กำลังดำเนินการอยู่
ดังนั้น
สิ่งนี้น่าจะเปลี่ยนจาก mainnet
เงินประกันเล็กน้อย
เพื่อป้องกันการทางด้านห้องนิรภัยเพราะ
มันเป็น
ระบบกระจายอำนาจแล้ว แต่จะแสดงให้คุณเห็น
ยอดเงินฝากทั้งหมด
และสิ่งที่ฉันเพิ่งทำคือฉันกดยืนยัน
แล้ว poco.js ของฉันก็ปรากฏขึ้น
ฉันลงนามในการทำธุรกรรมและสิ่งนี้จะ
ถูกบันทึก
ฉันคิดว่าเนื่องจากเราอยู่ในเบต้า
บนเครือข่ายทดสอบ
มีความล่าช้าเล็กน้อยที่นี่
ชั่วขณะ แต่สิ่งที่เกิดขึ้นใน
เบื้องหลังตอนนี้
เหมือนเรากำลังเล่นมายากลแบบนี้อยู่
ที่ห้องนิรภัยได้รับที่อยู่ btc ใหม่ดังนั้น
สำหรับทุกคำขอเราจะใช้
ที่อยู่การฝากใหม่สำหรับห้องนิรภัย
และเรากำลังสร้างสิ่งนี้บนเชนและ
เมื่อเสร็จแล้วคุณจะเห็นโดยทั่วไป
ที่นี่และจะขอให้คุณ
ส่ง
bitcoinจริงๆ ด้วยจำนวนเงินนั้นไปยัง
ที่อยู่ห้องนิรภัยเฉพาะนี้และคุณต้อง
ทำภายใน 24 ชั่วโมง
อืมหมายเหตุเล็กน้อย เราได้เพิ่ม
millibtc
นี้เพราะบางกระเป๋าเงิน bitcoin แสดงอย่างนั้น
และคุณยังสามารถสแกน
รหัส qr ได้
ใช้งานได้จริงกับกระเป๋าเงิน bitcoin ใด ๆ
ที่รองรับ test net
ดังนั้น electrum หรือคุณสามารถใช้
hardware wallet เช่น ledger หรือ trezor
อืม มันใช้งานได้ทั้งหมด
ฉันจะไม่ทำการจ่ายเงินตอนนี้ แต่
ในทางเทคนิคแล้ว สิ่งที่ฉันจะทำคือ
ตรงไปที่อิเลคตรอนของฉัน เพื่อจ่ายเงิน
ยังไงก็ตาม ฉันยังไม่ทำตอนนี้
แต่โดยพื้นฐานแล้ว สิ่งที่คุณจะเห็นคือ
นี่คือคำขอของฉันที่ฉันทำไป
อยู่ในระหว่างดำเนินการเพื่อ
ให้มันขอให้ฉันชำระเงินได้จริง
ซึ่งฉันยังไม่ได้ทำ
แต่ เอ่อ ถ้าฉันชำระเงินแล้ว
ได้รับการยืนยัน
บนบล็อคเชนของ bitcoin
คุณจะเห็นว่าคุณได้รับ
คำขอนี้
คุณจะได้รับข้อความแสดงความสำเร็จว่า จริงๆ คุณมี
polkabtc
และถ้าคุณไม่ทำถ้าคุณไม่
ชำระเงินภายใน 24 ชั่วโมง
เช่นคำขอจะถูกยกเลิก
และคุณได้รับการแจ้งเตือนว่า
ยกเลิกแล้ว
ใช่ปัญหาของขั้นตอนนี้
แค่เพียงหน้านี้
โดยทั่วไปแล้ว อย่างที่คุณเห็นบนนี้
ฉันมี polkabtc อยู่บ้าง
ดังนั้น อืม สิ่งที่ฉันทำได้คือ
ฉันสามารถทำการแลกได้
และเพื่อจุดประสงค์นี้ จริงๆ แล้ว ฉันจะ
สร้างที่อยู่
ตอนนี้
และelectrumให้ที่อยู่ใหม่กับฉัน
และ
ฉันจะตอบคำถามนี้ เอ่อ สมมติว่าฉัน
จะ
ต้องการถอน 0.003 polkabtc
ฉันจะกดยืนยันและอีกครั้งฉัน
ต้องลงนามในการทำธุรกรรม
และตอนนี้สิ่งที่เกิดขึ้น
เบื้องหลังคือ 1 ใน ตู้นิรภัยของเรา
ได้รับ
ร้องขอและควรส่ง bitcoin
ถึงฉัน
ไปยังที่อยู่ของฉันที่ฉันป้อนที่นี่และ
มันจะเด้งขึ้นมา
ลงที่นั่นและเมื่อ
รวมธุรกรรม bitcoin แล้วจริง ๆ มัน
จะเป็น
การถูกเพิ่ม ในอันนี้
และสิ่งที่คุณทำได้ตอนนี้คือ
สิ่งที่คุณเพิ่งเห็นก็คือเหตุการณ์
กำลังดำเนินการบน parachain
อืมและเมื่อเสร็จแล้วคุณยังสามารถ
คาดหวังสิ่งนี้ได้อย่างง่ายดาย
เอ่อตรวจสอบสิ่งนี้โดยใช้บ็อกซ์สตรีม
explorer
อืม ฉันจะรออีกแปปนึงนะ
เพื่อให้มันสมบูรณ์ใช่ดังนั้น
โดยทั่วไป
อืม นี่เป็นเพียงการยืนยัน
และใช่ปัญหาที่ง่ายมากในการแลก
และสิ่งสุดท้าย
ที่ฉันต้องการแสดงนั้นโดยพื้นฐานแล้ว
การโอนดังนั้นเมื่อคุณมี polkabtc
สิ่งที่จะเกิดขึ้นคือคุณสามารถ
โอนทั่วๆไป
และสิ่งที่คุณจะใส่ที่นี่คือเอ่อ
ที่อยู่ของคุณเองดังนั้น
บางทีฉันแค่จะคัดลอกและวางที่อยู่ฉันเอง
แบบรวดเร็ว
และ อืม สิ่งที่เราเพิ่งเพิ่มเข้าไปนั้นโดยพื้นฐานแล้ว
เมื่อ xcm ทำงานได้อย่างสมบูรณ์ คุณก็ทำได้
เพียงแค่โอนไปยัง acala
หรือ plasm หรืออื่นๆ
โปรเจ็คอื่นๆ ที่เริ่มทำงานแล้ว และ
จะเชื่อมต่อกันเป็น parachains um
และฉันแค่จะทำการโอนที่นี่
ตอนนี้
เอ่อ โอเค ฉันไม่มีเงินพอ
ส่งสิ่งนี้
สิ่งนี้น่าจะใช้ได้
ใช้เวลาสักครู่ในการโอนอีกครั้ง
และเมื่อเสร็จแล้วมันจะแสดง a
pop-up เล็กๆ ตรงนี้ แต่อีกครั้ง เรา
กำลังไลฟ์อยู่
และนั่นก็คือ
นั่นคือพื้นฐานสำหรับการสาธิตเทคโนโลยี
อืม มีแค่
เอ่อ ประกาศเล็กมาก อืม
โปรดไปที่เบต้า เพื่อทดสอบ
เรามีความสุขมากสำหรับ
ข้อเสนอแนะทุกอันที่เราได้รับ
และหวังว่าจะสามารถปรับปรุงระบบได้
ยิ่งไปกว่านั้น
อืมถ้าคุณมีคำถามเพิ่มเติมเช่น
สามารถติดต่อเราได้ทาง discord
ทวิตเตอร์ และเทเลแกรมของเราก็เปิดอยู่
และสิ่งสุดท้ายที่สำคัญคือเรา
มีกิจกรรมล่าขุมทรัพย์เกิดขึ้น
อืม มีเงินรางวัลรวม 500 dot
สำหรับ
ผู้ใช้ 500 คนแรกที่เจอปัญหาและ
แลกรับคำขอในเครือข่ายทดสอบของเรา
ดังนั้นโปรดไปที่ betapokerbtc.io และ
ตรวจสอบ ภารกิจ
ขอบคุณ
สุดยอดมาก อรุณสวัสดิ์
ทุกคน
นี่คือเบ็ตตี้ผู้ร่วมก่อตั้ง acala และเรา
มีไบรอันเป็นผู้ร่วมก่อตั้งและ cto ของ
acala วันนี้กับเราและเขา
ได้เตรียม
cross chain แบบเต็มรูปแบบในการสาธิต defi สำหรับคุณ
ฉันจะทำให้มันสั้นและกระชับ
เกี่ยวกับการแนะนำของฉัน
ก่อนที่เราจะเจาะลึกลงไป เนื่องจาก
acala เริ่มมีมาประมาณ
ปีที่แล้วเราก็ทำการสาธิต polka defi
เดียวกันอีกครั้ง
เราได้เรียกใช้ defi แอปพลิเคชั่นครบชุดแล้ว
แล้วมันก็เยี่ยมมาก
ที่ได้เห็นในปีนี้
แอปพลิเคชั่นทำงาน
มันเหมือนว่า
เราเข้าใกล้จุดวิสัยทัศน์
ที่ควรจะเป็น
อืมและมันคุ้มค่าที่จะแบ่งปัน
สื่งที่เราคิดเกี่ยวกับอนาคต
อาจดูเหมือน อืม ฉันคิดว่าเรามีคุณ
รู้จักบิตคอยน์
ซึ่งเป็นข้อผิดพลาดของการคำนวน อย่างหนึ่ง
แล้ว ethereum
อาจเป็นข้อผิดพลาดของเมนเฟรม uh ของ
blockchain และตอนนี้ฉันคิดว่าเรากำลัง
เข้าสู่
คลาวด์คอมพิวติ้ง
ที่ทุกอย่างเป็นบริการ
นั่นคือที่ที่เรากำลังมุ่งหน้าไป ฉันคิดว่า อืม
เราเชื่อว่าคุณรู้อนาคต
จะเป็นเอ่อ multi-chain
อืม แล้วก็ความเชี่ยวชาญ เอ่อ มันคือ
การเอาชนะ
เอ่อ ลักษณะทั่วไป ดังนั้นคุณจะ
เชนของคุณ จะ
สามารถเฉพาะในโดเมนเฉพาะและทำ
บางสิ่งบางอย่างได้ดีจริงๆและแก้ไข
ปัญหาบางอย่างได้เป็นอย่างดี
อืมแล้วการเปลี่ยนแปลงก็ไม่ควรเข้มงวดด้วย
ควรจะอัพเกรดได้
นั่นคือสิ่งที่เราคิดว่ามันเป็น
สิ่งที่กำลังจะเกิดและยัง
ที่เรานำคำพูดของเราออกมาและสร้างแอปพลิเคชัน
ของเรา
นี่คือ acala stack อืมถ้าคุณ
เอ่อยังไม่ได้ดูอันนี้เลย um acala
คือ full-fledged
blockchain
แต่มันคือ ledger และไว้วางใจได้โดย
polkadot นี่คือ
คุณรู้ไหม
ในแง่ของ
ความปลอดภัยของเครือข่าย หรือ
trust as a service
อืมมันอยู่ระหว่างกลาง
acala's defi ของการเสนอ
พวกเขาเสนอ รูปแบบการบริการ
เหมือนโมดูลที่ปรับแต่งได้ใช่เลย
ตัวอย่างเช่นคุณรู้ว่าเรามีสิ่งนี้
multi-coleto stablecoin สนับสนุนโดย
dot
สภาพคล่องdot
คุณรู้ว่าbitcoin เหมือน polkaBTC สามารถใช้ได้
เป็นหลักประกันด้วย
อืม แล้วเราก็การชำระบัญชีของเรา
แบบอัตโนมัติและ
ใช้ลูกผสมของ amm dex และการประมูล
อืม กับ อืม แล้วก็อีกอย่างที่ฉัน
คิดว่าไบรอันจะสาธิตคุณจริงๆ
วันนี้เป็นการ stake สภาพคล่อง ดังนั้นนี่คือ
การstake tokken dot หรือ ldot
ช่วยให้คุณได้รับเงินรางวัล
จากการ stake ในขณะที่ให้ผลผลิตใน defi
แบบ trustlessly
และคุณยังสามารถพูดได้ว่าคุณรู้ evm คือ
โมดูล
บนโมดูลบริการ
เราเข้ากันได้อย่างเต็มที่
กับ evm คุณสามารถสร้างสมาร์ท
คอนแทรคได้ หรือแดปทุกชนิด
บน acala โดยพื้นฐานแล้ว
acala เสนอ
defi as a service
เรากำลังจะสาธิตในวันนี้
น่าจะเป็นจุดเริ่มต้น คุณจะ
เห็น
composable services นั่นหมายถึง
dapps สามารถประกอบกันได้
ที่ได้รับ
แต่ยังมีสมาร์ทคอนแทรคและ dapps
จากบล็อคเชนอื่นๆ จะเป็น
สามารถประกอบกันได้ด้วย acala
และใครก็ตามที่คุณรู้จักที่สามารถทำได้
ทำธุรกรรมร่วมกัน อืม หวังว่า
คุณจะได้สัมผัสมันในวันนี้
และนั่นคือการแนะนำตัวของฉัน ฉันจะส่งให้
ให้ brianพูดต่อ
ให้ฉัน
แชร์หน้าจอของฉัน
คุณควรจะเห็นหน้าจอของฉัน
ตอนนี้
นี่คือ tesะnet ของเรา นี่ไม่ใช่
mandala testenet ที่เรากำลังดำเนินการอยู่
นี่คือที่โดยเฉพาะในการทำ
parachain test net ดังนั้นมัน
กำลังเชื่อมต่อกับ rococo เวอร์ชันของเรา
คุณจะเห็นว่าเรามีบาง
Parachain เชื่อมต่อกับมัน
และ
เราจะได้แสดง
การสาธิตมาเริ่มกันเลยดีกว่า
สิ่งแรก
คุณอาจต้องการทำสิ่งนี้ คือ
คุณควรมี
ตัวแปร อยู่แล้วบ้าง เช่น dots หรือ
bitcoin
หรืออาจจะเป็น ethereum ในกรณีนี้
ถ้าอย่างนั้นคุณมี bitcoin อยู่แล้ว
คุณสามารถใช้ได้
polkabtc โดยใช้bitcoin
ในการทำ polkabtc
โดยการโอนมาเป็น polkabtc
บน acala เห็นได้ชัดว่ามีการถ่ายโอน
จะมีค่าธรรมเนียมบางอย่าง
แล้วเมื่อคุณมี polkabtc
มีบางอย่างที่คุณทำได้
กับมัน
สิ่งหนึ่งที่คุณสามารถขายได้
แต่นั้น
อาจไม่ใช่ความคิดที่ดีที่สุด จริงๆ แล้ว
มันสามารถทำเงินได้โดยไม่ต้องขาย
พวกมันไป
นั่นคือที่โปรโตคอลของ stable coin
มันสะดวก
เพื่อเราจะได้เริ่มต้น
เงินกู้ใหม่ได้โดยใช้ polkabtc เป็นเงินฝาก
สมมุติว่าฉันสามารถฝาก 0.2 polkabtc
ของฉันได้ ฉันจะสามารถยืมได้ถึง
ในกรณีนี้ 7000$ ฉันสามารถ
ยืมมาทั้งหมดแล้วคุณจะเห็น
ราคาการชำระบัญชีของฉันคือตัวเลขนี้
และอัตราส่วนปัจจุบันของฉันคือ 120%
ดังนั้นนี่คือ นี่มีความอันตรายเล็กน้อย
ดังนั้น
ดังนั้นบางทีมันอาจจะเป็นความคิดที่ดี
ที่จะยืมน้อยกว่านี้เล็กน้อยเพื่อที่ฉันจะได้ค่อนข้างมั่นใจ
ทั้งคู่
ไม่น่าเป็นไปได้ที่ราคา bitcoin จะลดลงถึง
30,000$
หวังว่า
ลำดับที่สอง แค่รีวิว ก็จะมี
ค่าธรรมเนียมอัตราดอกเบี้ยบางส่วนใน
การยืม
นั่นคืออัตราส่วนของฉัน
ฉันสามารถทำการเปลี่ยนแปลงได้
ใช่แล้วจะได้เงินสามพัน
ขออภัย 5000 acala usd
จาก polkabtc ที่ฉันฝากไว้
ตอนนี้มีเงินแล้ว ฉันสามารถ
ทำอะไรกับมัน
เรามีการแลกเปลี่ยนดังนั้นจึงมี dex
ที่คุณสามารถใช้ได้
ใช้ usd ซื้ออื่นๆ
สินทรัพย์อื่นๆ ดังนั้นคุณจะสามารถซื้อได้ด้วย
สินทรัพย์ อื่นด้วยเช่นกัน
รวมทั้ง polkabtc และ dot และ
btc
และทรัพย์สินอื่นๆ อีกเล็กน้อยในอนาคต
ดังนั้นในกรณีนี้บางทีฉันอยากจะซื้อ
dots บางส่วน ที่เห็นได้ชัด
เป็นความคิดที่ดี เพื่อให้ฉันสามารถใช้จ่ายได้
1,000 ausd ซึ่งจะซื้อได้dots
ได้จำนวนนี้
เมื่อได้รับการยืนยันแล้ว
เมื่อคุณมีความคิด
ถ้าคุณจะไม่ใช้มัน
ทันทีอาจเป็นความคิดที่ดีที่จะ
stake พวกมัน เพื่อให้คุณได้รับเงินจากการ stake
เป็นรางวัลตอบแทน
ซึ่งมีผลตอบแทนที่ดีพอสมควร
คุณสามารถไปที่เครือข่าย polkadot เพื่อทำ
การstake หรือวิธีอื่นคือการใช้สภาพคล่อง
โปรโตคอล stake เพื่อทำการstake ซึ่งเป็น
การทำที่ง่ายกว่ามาก นี่คือ UI แบบเร่งด่วน
ดังนั้นคุณเพียงแค่ป้อนจำนวนdots
ที่คุณต้องการ stake
และคลิกที่ปุ่ม stake และนั่นคือ
ทั้งหมดที่คุณต้องทำเพื่อstake dot และ
โปรโตคอลมีการกระจายอำนาจและโปรโตคอล
จะ
จัดการการเลือกข้อมูลทั้งหมด
การเสนอชื่อ ฯลฯ
แต่แน่นอนว่าคุณยังสามารถโหวตให้ validators
ที่ชื่นชอบหากคุณต้องการด้วย
ด้วย
ldots ดังนั้นตอนนี้ฉันได้เปลี่ยน dotsทั้งหมดของฉันด้วย
ldots และ
แล้วคุณจะทำได้ในภายหลังและ
ลงคะแนนสำหรับข้อมูลเมตาถ้าคุณต้องการ
ทำงานเกี่ยวกับ ui สำหรับพื้นที่นี้
นี่คือหน้าจอเมาส์ดังนั้น
คุณสามารถดูประวัติที่คุณสามารถทำได้ถ้าคุณ
ต้องการแลกคุณทำได้
คุณทำได้ แค่รอ
เวลาในการ unbounding ซึ่งจะเป็น
เจ็ดวันสำหรับคุซามะ 28 วันบน
polkadot
แล้วก็รอ แล้วเราจะไม่
เก็บค่าใช้จ่าย
จากคุณเป็นค่าธรรมเนียมการไถ่ถอนพิเศษ แต่ถ้าคุณ
ต้องการเงินจริงๆตอนนี้
จนถึงจำนวนที่กำหนด แล้วคุณจะ
สามารถไถ่ถอนได้
ทันที แต่เราจะเรียกเก็บเงินคุณ
ค่าธรรมเนียมการไถ่ถอนบางส่วนเพราะ
คุณกำลังข้ามช่วงเวลาunbounded แต่
ถ้าคุณต้องการจริงๆ
คุณสามารถเสีย dots บางส่วนได้
เพื่อความสะดวก
ดังนั้นตอนนี้คุณมี ldot และ คุณ
ผลตอบแทนของการ stake และคุณจะ
ซื้ออัตราบูสต์เพิ่มขึ้น
ได้อย่างไร
จาก dot ดังนั้นวิธีอื่นที่จะทำ
คือ
เอ่อ ตัวอย่างเช่น คุณสามารถทำได้คือ
เพิ่มสภาพคล่องให้กับ dex ของเรา ให้มี
โดยพื้นฐานแล้วจะมี ausd
จำนวนหนึ่งและสินทรัพย์ของคุณจำนวนมาก
จากนั้นคุณจะจัดหา
สภาพคล่องให้กับ dex ของเรา
และจะ
หากผู้คนทำการซื้อขาย
คุณจะได้รับรายได้เพิ่มเติม
เป็นค่าธรรมเนียมเพิ่มเติมเป็นรางวัล เรายังมีโปรแกรมจูงใจ
ให้รางวัลด้านสภาพคล่อง ดังนั้นคุณ
ในขณะเดียวกัน
นอกเหนือจากค่าธรรมเนียมที่คุณมี
usd เพิ่มเติม
เป็นรางวัลเช่นกัน
นี่คือการเพิ่มสภาพคล่องให้กับ
dex
ในภายหลังหากคุณต้องการ
แลกสภาพคล่องแลกโทเค็นกลับ
ได้ในภายหลัง
อืมใช่ ดังนั้นสิ่งต่อไปฉันจะ
แสดงให้คุณเห็นอย่างรวดเร็วเล็กน้อยนี่คือ
ยังมีความคืบหน้าในการทำงานอีกครั้งและเรา
ยังคงสรุปรายละเอียดทั้งหมดและ
กำลังสรุป ui แต่เรามี
คุณสมบัติการกำกับดูแล
ดังนั้นมันจะค่อนข้างคล้ายกับ polkadot
หรือ kusama แต่จะซับซ้อนมากกว่าเล็กน้อย
เรามี honzon councilซึ่งจะ
เป็นคนหนึ่งที่จัดการ
stable coin โปรโตคอล
สำหรับ homa councilฉันจึงจัดการ
สำหรับ
liquid staking protocol สำหรับ ผู้ถือเก่า
คุณจะสามารถเข้าร่วม
homa council
โดยใช้ ldot ของคุณเพื่อลงคะแนนให้ um
ในฐานะผู้ถือ acala คุณจะเป็น
ผู้สามารถเข้าร่วมได้
general council และ honzon
council
ใช่แล้ว พวกนั้นยังคงทำงานเพื่อหนทางต่างๆ
ดังนั้นมัน
จึงไม่ว่างเปล่า แต่หวังว่าในตอนต่อไป
เราจะมีอะไรอีกมากมาย
บน test netของเรา
ตอนนี้คุณก็มีแล้ว
มีความคิดที่ทำกำไรได้
ในขณะที่คุณนอนหลับ
สิ่งที่คุณทำได้
อีกอย่างคือ
ในขณะที่ฉันแสดงให้คุณเห็นฉันสร้าง ausd ออกมา
จำนวนมาก
จาก polkabtc ของฉันแล้วสิ่งต่อไป
ถ้าฉันอยาก
เพิ่มกำไรของฉันโดยการรับความเสี่ยง
มากขึ้นฉันสามารถโอน
acala usd ของฉันไปยังเครือข่ายlaminar
โดยโอนเข้าบัญชี
เอาเป็นว่าจะโอน 2000 ยังไง
มาทำการโอนข้ามเชนกัน
จาก acala ถึง laminar เพื่อให้คุณเห็น
วิธีการคือ
x token โอนไปยัง parachain ดังนั้นสิ่งนี้จะ
โอนเงินมาไป
เมนเน็ต laminar นี่จะเป็น
การทำ
การโอนข้ามเชนและสิ่งนี้จะใช้เวลา
เวลาเพิ่มขึ้นเล็กน้อยดังนั้นในขณะนี้
ที่มันกำลังโอนอยู่ ฉันจะรีบโชว์บางอย่าง
ด้านลามิเนตดังนั้นสมมติว่า
โอนแล้ว
สมมติว่าฉันได้ ausd แล้ว
แล้วฉันจะสามารถ
ทำการเปลี่ยน เพื่อให้สิ่งนี้จะช่วยให้
คุณได้
ทำการซื้อขายด้วยสินทรัพย์ที่ละเอียดอ่อนดังนั้น
จะมี
เช่นการแลกเปลี่ยนสินทรัพย์ forex
หรือ
เช่นเดียวกับสิ่งอื่น ๆ เช่นทองและน้ำมันเป็นต้น
สมมติว่าฉันต้องการซื้อเงินยูโร
อาจเป็นเพราะ
ฉันจะไปเที่ยวยุโรปแล้ว
บางที
บางทีฉันอยากมี
เงินยูโร
เลยแลก ausd บ้าง
สู่ยูโรลามินาร์
และฉันก็สามารถทำมาร์จิ้นได้เช่นกัน
สำหรับการซื้อขาย ตัวอย่างเช่น
เลเวอเรจ เทรด bitcoin หรือ เลเวอเรจ เทรด
ethereum หรือเพียงแค่ทำ
การซื้อขายฟอเร็กซ์ของฉัน
เพื่อให้ฉันสามารถฝากเงินเข้า um
the margin pool
ฉันบอกได้เลยว่าฉันเลือกได้มากถึง 20
เท่า เลเวอเรจ ในกรณีนี้ ดังนั้น
เพื่อตัดสินใจซื้อขายมาร์จิ้น
ใช่ มาเปิดตำแหน่งกันเถอะ ฉันจะ
เริ่มที่ 20 เท่า
การเปิดรับการซื้อขาย usbjpy
เอ่อ แบบนี้กับการโอนข้ามเชน
ได้แสดงว่า ทำสำเร็จแล้ว
มาดูเหตุการณ์กัน
เราเลยต้องโอนโทเค็นข้ามเชน
ที่นี่คุณจะเห็นว่ากำลังส่ง
ข้อความรีเลย์ ดังนั้น จาก
พาราเชน ถึง พาราเชน
ข้อความเอ่อเกี่ยวข้องกับ
รีเลย์เชน ซึ่งเป็นโรโคโค
ของโรโคโคในกรณีนี้เป็นต้น
ด้านลามิเนตที่คุณเห็น
เรามีงานฝาก
ควรเป็นอันนี้ดังนั้น uh ดังนั้น 2000 ausd คือ
การฝากเข้าบัญชีนี้
ดังนั้นนี่คือโดยทั่วไป อืมดังนั้น
โดยพื้นฐานแล้ว
การถ่ายโอนข้ามเชน usd ระหว่างนั้น
acala
และลามิน่า
นั่นคือทั้งหมดของการสาธิตที่ฉันจะ
แสดงให้คุณเห็น
อืม สุดท้ายแต่ไม่ท้ายสุด
เรากำลังทำงานกับ xcm
เกี่ยวกับการใช้โทเค็นการทำงาน สิ่งนี้
จะอนุญาต
ทุกอย่างรวมทั้งอื่นๆ
พาราเชนถึง
ง่ายกว่าแค่เขียนโหวต
ซึ่งกันและกัน
เราได้สร้าง
open runtime module libraryและสร้างบางส่วน
ของสินทรัพย์การโอนโทเค็นข้ามเชน
ซึ่งเป็นแบบที่ใช้โดย
บางโครงการรวมถึง
platinum
vala และอีกสองสามแห่ง
อืมเพื่อดำเนินการโอนข้ามเชน
ฉันก็เลยสร้าง
คู่มือการนำไปใช้และ um
แผนการดำเนินงานบางอย่างใน
อนาคตสู่
เพิ่มเติมช่วยให้ทุกคนดำเนินการ
crosschain เป็นการโอนเงิน
จึงจะทำให้ทุกคนสามารถ
เขียน
กันได้ง่ายขึ้นเพียงแค่
บูรณาการ
library ของเรานั่นคือทั้งหมดที่ฉันมี
สำหรับคุณวันนี้
centrifuge คือ
การนำทรัพย์สิน
สินทรัพย์ในโลกแห่งความเป็นจริง มาใช้บน defi เราจึงอนุญาต
ธุรกิจ
เช่น เอ่อ นักลงทุนด้านอสังหาริมทรัพย์หรือ
อืมเหมือนธุรกิจที่ต้องการเงินทุน
ที่ต้องการหารายได้
และใช้ defi เป็นแหล่งสภาพคล่อง
แทนที่จะไป
ไปที่ธนาคาร วิธี
วิธีอธิบายที่ง่ายที่สุดคือเรา
อนุญาตให้จัดเรียงสินทรัพย์
ในโลกแห่งความเป็นจริงที่ไม่สามารถเปลี่ยนได้ ทั้งหมดเหล่านี้
ลงในพูลประเภทต่าง ๆ เช่น
เรามี
บ้านที่ผู้ใช้ของเราสามารถสร้างพูลได้
ที่นักลงทุนสามารถลงทุน ที่เราดึง
เงินนั้นแล้ว
ผู้กู้ประเภทต่าง ๆ สามารถยืม
สภาพคล่องได้จากพูลนั้น
โดยการฝากประเภทที่ไม่สามารถเปลี่ยนได้
โทเค็นที่แสดงถึง
ความเป็นสินทรัพย์ลงในพูลนั้น
ประวัติเล็กน้อยเกี่ยวกับcentrifuge
เราเริ่มที่จะสร้าง
บนระบบ คล้ายระบบนิเวศ defiนี้
เกือบๆ
สามปี ที่แล้วจริงๆ
ก่อนที่ d5 จะเป็นจริง ๆ และจาก
ตอนแรกบอกว่าโอเค ทำอย่างไร
จะอนุญาต
เอ่อธุรกิจที่ยังไม่ได้หรือ
ผู้ใช้ที่ยังไม่มี crypto to
ชนิดของการโต้ตอบ
ในระบบนี้และนั่นคือเหตุผลที่เราไป
กับ
อืม ความคิดแบบนี้ที่จะนำมา
สินทรัพย์ใหม่ไปยัง d5 อนุญาตใหม่
สภาพคล่อง
ความหลากหลาย สินทรัพย์ประเภทต่างๆ
คลาสที่คุณไม่มีวันนี้
แล้วก็
เราเปิดตัวจริงบน ethereum
ปีที่แล้ว อืม ประเภทของผลิตภัณฑ์ที่เรา
เรียก ทิน เลค
ที่ให้คุณลงทุนใน
ในทรัพย์สินที่แตกต่างกันเหล่านี้และฉันจะ
ให้คุณ
ภาพรวมคร่าวๆ ว่าหน้าตาเป็นอย่างไร
แต่เรามีสิ่งที่เราเรียกว่าสินทรัพย์
ผู้ริเริ่ม
ผู้ทรงสร้างสระน้ำที่แตกต่างกันเหล่านี้เรา
มีตัวอย่างที่ฉันพูดถึงของจริง
เงินกู้สะพานอสังหาริมทรัพย์
ดังนั้นนี่คือพูล เอ่อ 1.6 ล้านตาย
ประมาณห้า
ที่ฉันได้รับอัตราดอกเบี้ยห้าเปอร์เซ็นต์
ถ้าฉันลงทุนในพูลนี้
และฉันเห็นว่ามี
ที่เป็น
ห้าสินเชื่อที่แตกต่างกันอย่างต่อเนื่องที่
ในขณะที่พวกเขาจ่ายดอกเบี้ยต่างกัน
อัตราที่มีวันครบกำหนดต่างกัน
จำนวนที่แตกต่างกันและฉันสามารถเห็นการเรียงลำดับของ
ข้อมูลทั้งหมดนี้คือ
อยู่ในห่วงโซ่เหมือนที่จริงฉัน
ผู้ใช้พลังของทินเลคตัวเอง
และกระเป๋าเงินใบนี้ที่ฉัน
ใช้สาธิต
อืม ฉันมีเงินลงทุนในส่วนต่างๆ เหล่านี้
โทเค็นและทั้งหมดนี้เป็นรายได้
ดอกเบี้ย
กับของจริงที่แตกต่างกันเหล่านี้
ทรัพย์สินของโลกถูกต้องและฉันก็เข้าใจ
ฉันได้ใช้ defi กับทรัพย์สินที่เป็น
ไม่สัมพันธ์กันอย่างสมบูรณ์ เสถียรอย่างยิ่ง
และให้ฉันแบบนี้ว่าทั้งหมด
ข้อดีที่โจรมีด้วย
กับความมั่นคงมั่นคงที่เอิ่ม
ว่าเป็นหนึ่งใน
คลาสสินทรัพย์ปลอดภัยกลับมาแล้ว
ไปที่สไลด์
และกำลังพูดถึงว่าทำไมเราถึง
พูดถึงเรื่องนี้ที่
อืม วันสาธิต อืม ประเภทของอาคารและ
การสร้างทั้งหมดนี้เรารู้จากมาก
ในช่วงต้นนั้นเช่น
ethereum จะไม่ให้
scalability ที่เราต้องการ
แต่เราก็รู้ดีว่าเราจำเป็นต้อง
บูรณาการเราจำเป็นต้องติดต่อกับทุกคน
โปรโตคอลและผู้ผลิตที่มีข้อบกพร่องอื่น ๆ เหล่านี้
และ ave เป็น
โครงการของเราที่เรากำลังดำเนินการอยู่จริงๆ
อย่างใกล้ชิดแล้ว
และด้วยเหตุนั้นเมื่อเรา um
เมื่อเรานึกถึงเครื่องหมุนเหวี่ยง เราก็จะได้
ได้รับสำหรับ
สักพักก็คิดว่าโอเค
เราไม่ได้อยู่อย่างโดดเดี่ยว เราไม่มี
แค่มีตัวตนบน ethereum เรามีอยู่จริง
อืม ยอมให้สิ่งที่เราเรียกว่ากรดของเรา
ผู้สร้างสะพานเชื่อมกรดเหล่านี้เข้ากับ
ไปทุกที่ที่จำเป็นและเพื่อ
ตัวอย่างเป็นหลักทรัพย์ค้ำประกันใน akala
เอ่อ เอาไปใส่ในคอมหรือผู้ผลิต
อืมและดังนั้น
อืม อะไรนะ
ที่สำคัญตรงนี้คือ
ส่วนนี้อยู่ในห่วงโซ่กากบาทตรงกลาง
ข้อความในการเชื่อมโยง
และจะกลับมาอีกสักหน่อยเกี่ยวกับ
ชอบที่ d5 มาจากไหนและชอบทำไม
ethereum ได้เห็นสิ่งนี้ อืม บ้าไปแล้ว
จำนวนกิจกรรม
ที่จริงฉันคิดว่ามันเป็นหนึ่งในสิ่งนี้
สิ่งที่ฉลาดที่สุดที่ระบบนิเวศนี้ทำได้
ได้ทำเป็นมาตรฐานรอบ ๆ
โทเค็น erc20 นี้
เราได้สร้างมาตรฐานที่
ใช้งานง่ายมาก
และนั่นทำให้คุณสามารถรวมเข้าด้วยกันได้จริง
โปรโตคอลตามอำเภอใจในการให้กู้ยืม
โปรโตคอลกับตลาดเงินด้วย
การแลกเปลี่ยนแบบกระจายอำนาจกับ
ผู้รวบรวม
จากนั้นคุณสามารถสร้างโทเค็นการห่อและ
นำไปรวมไว้ในกลุ่มสภาพคล่องและรับ
โทเค็นมากขึ้นและ
ทั่วๆ ไปก็ประมาณนี้
ขั้นพื้นฐาน
อืม มาตรฐาน มันไม่สมบูรณ์แบบแต่มัน
ทำงาน
ได้ดี ฉันบอกแบบนั้น
คิดถึง polka dot
อืม มัน
มันซับซ้อนกว่าเล็กน้อยใช่มั้ย
ในสาระสำคัญเรายังคง
ฉันคิดว่ามีเครื่องมือและมันเป็น
ในแบบของเรา
อืมเพื่อประโยชน์สูงสุดของเราและฉันต้องการ
พูดคุยเกี่ยวกับเรา
ฉันหมายถึงพวกเราทุกคนได้รับการสาธิตที่นี่
ทุกคนที่กำลังสร้างบน polkadot
ให้คิดว่าเราจะสร้างอย่างไร
การทำงานร่วมกันนี้
บน polkadot เป็นระบบนิเวศจาก
เริ่มต้นให้ดีจะได้ไม่ต้อง
มีสิ่งเหล่านี้
อแดปเตอร์หลายพันตัวและอื่นๆ
อืม อะไรนะ
Miguel จะพูดถึงอะไรสักหน่อย
ต่อไปคือการที่เราเริ่มต้นสิ่งนี้
อืม เราเริ่มเน็ตทดสอบอีกแล้ว
ที่เราอยากพูดคุยกันสักนิด
ที่จะช่วย
คนที่สร้างบนคนแต่
ตั้งแต่เช้าตรู่
ชี้เวลาเพื่อเริ่มคิดเกี่ยวกับ
การบูรณาการและฉันคิดว่ามันเยี่ยมมากที่
akala ตัวอย่างเช่น
แสดงให้เห็นว่าพวกเขาใช้ hoga btc
เพื่อเป็นหลักประกันในการสะระแหน่เหมือนอย่างอื่น
มั่นคงตรงจุด แล้วเราจะทำเช่นไร
สร้างสิ่งนั้นและอืมบางทีฉันจะทิ้งมันไว้
เพื่อ Miguel แนะนำต่อไป
เรากำลังทำอะไรกับสิ่งนั้น
ขอบคุณ อืม ให้ฉันแชร์หน้าจอของฉันตอนนี้
ใช่ที่นี่
เอาล่ะ อืม อุ๊ปส์ ที่ไม่ใช่คนเดียว
คุณเห็นหน้าจอของฉันไหม
ขอบคุณค่ะ
หลังจากดูการนำเสนอนี้แล้ว ฉัน
คิดว่าเป็นภาคต่อที่ดีที่จะแนะนำ
ต่อไป
chad chai เป็นการสืบทอดแบบ rococo
เชน
เอ่อ เทาเน็ตและเมื่อเรารู้จักกันแล้ว
เริ่มการทดสอบกับ centrifuge ของเรา
เชนวิธีการแปลงของเรา
เชนของเรากับพาราเชน เอ่อ ใช้
cumulus เราตระหนักว่าอาจมี
ประโยชน์อื่นๆ
of sharing this uh this environment with
with many other projects
and uh so we did that so trajectory is a
public
test not based on on rococo
so and the whole purpose is to to
support
the onboarding and the testing towards
rococo by just
on boarding a product chains earlier on
you know figuring out the
the issues um that they
can come from there from their own run
time or
in addition to tests that will net fully
networked
uh deployments and importantly enough
the interoperability with with other
power chains like
like lucas was uh was mentioning
so um yeah
so we a little bit of the you know the
features
that has uh is that
it is a clone of rococo so it will
always be
at par with rococo codebase meaning
um you know the tree of cumulus
substrate polka dot repos
that we wanted to keep always in at par
with rococo so
there's less surprises whenever your
product chain is
is included in or about to be included
in in the regular contestant
the idea is to have um frequent recycles
so
we will include many many product chains
we will maybe make changes on
on some of the runtime um to allow
certain test cases to be to be verified
but ideas that will cycle fast and it's
immediate available available
immediately
so you can just follow the following
instructions i will
i will uh mention in a moment but
there's no waiting list so as soon as
you get in
um and you send the proposal on the
registration form
then you will get in um so yeah the
whole point as well is to try to
to make emphasis more on this
interoperability of barack chains so we
try to set up the correct configuration
for cross chain messaging palettes
and try to support as much as possible
this uh
any project to to start moving messages
assets tokens non-fungible fungible
around us as soon as possible
so if we uh look at briefly about the
registration process
is basically the same as rococo when you
need to run a few validators
one collater you have to fill up a form
um which i can show you here it's same
almost copy paste from rococo um just
provide your
you know element handle your account
address so we can keep track of
which account to send some funds um
departure id
so before um you know whenever we
actually recycle or cycle the
the uh the the chain then we
can send funds uh towards your your
account without having to
uh for you to go through that process
again
um yeah please go to the chat channel in
in element and uh and try to yeah just
ask any questions you want uh for
support i will
we will help you to get that going and
um of course everything right now is
on the the wikipedia wiki as a
as another uh source of uh you know
documentation
so feel free to follow these steps and
we already onboarded a few
parachutes and it was pretty painless
um you can see i can show you
the the ui at the moment that we have
where we have a few product chains
onboarded
and then it's open for proposals so
um yeah feel free to to follow these
steps and start testing the interchange
communication
um yeah thank you hi everyone it's
really exciting to be here and take part
to part of this of this uh i think uh
unique day right
so hopefully you guys see my screen i
think you do um
all right so let's get to it so yeah
my name is alberto i'm the developer
relations manager at pure state which is
the company
building moonbeam the project that i'm
going to talk to you
about today so it's basically a smart
contract protein with ethereum
compatibility
so the presentation will have a brief
introduction uh of mubim
and then we have a very special demo to
show you guys and
uh later on today i'll be joined by
joe who is the cto of sushi swap and
boring crypto which is uh the our lead
architect of the bento box
at sushi swap so very excited to have
them on board as well
so i guess the first question we have to
ask ourselves it's
what it's moonbeam and the most basic
definition is that
moonbeam is an ethereum compatible smart
contract platform
basically at its core it's uh it has an
evm
so this means that it it provides
compatibility for solidity smart
contracts
or actually anything that compiles to to
evm bytecode
then we have different layers of
functionalities on top of the evm
the first one being a web 3 rpc as you
can see here
so this means that we're compatible with
all the ethereum-based tools that you
know and love already
such as metamask truffle remix hard hat
we have a bunch of documentation and
have you can use these tools
on moonbeam our test set for example
mumbai safa today
and also another great part of moonbeam
is that we have
basically uh we have worked around
the we have modified the underlying
account system of our
para chain to standardize it where we
standardize the account and key format
to that of ethereum this is really
exciting because it means that when you
interact with our evm
you're going to use your ethereum
account and your ethereum private key as
you would do right now on ethereum
but then would you move to other like
substrate based features or like parity
in
standard features like governance or
staking which we just basically roll out
to our tested
a few weeks ago you're going to do all
that as well
with the same ethereum account and
private key which is very exciting for
us to share this with you
and on top of all we have we have been
building a great ecosystem of different
integrations
a lot of them are defy oriented but we
have other great integrations as well
and we're truly excited about the
ecosystem we're building
so why does a multi-chain strategy make
sense and
for the sake of this presentation i'm
only going to talk about the topic in
the middle
and this is this is basically that new
projects can be first movers in new
markets right
and a lot of these projects uh can can
access
through moonbeam to assets that are not
native uh
natively available on ethereum right so
they can connect through moonbeam to
either polkadot and kusama and accent
access not only dot or ksm
but a growing list of perichine-based
assets
and we think this is important because
this provides just a new whole market
that they can tap
into and uh how does moonbeam
plays out in this multi-chain uh world
right so
basically let's say that you have your
solidity-based smart contracts and you
can either have them deployed to
ethereum
and then just let's say that you're
using this this uh very common tool
called truffle or let's say hard hat or
whatever
and you have uh truffle or hard hat set
up to deploy these contracts to a theme
right
and just by changing or adding the
provider of mumbai's alpha or tesla for
example
you can display those contracts exactly
the same without with minor
modifications if
if if if needed because it sometimes
then you don't have to do any
modifications
to moonbeam and and we have had a lot of
feedback from projects saying that it's
just unbelievably
simple to do so and this means that if
you do so
you you'll your contracts will leave a
moonbeam but more importantly you'll
have
access to the whole polkadot ecosystem
of other pair of chains
so which is just basically great to do
so right
and some of the projects that are
working on moonbeam include
uh for example sushi swap yesterday we
announced that bouncer is coming to
mumbing which is very exciting for us
we also have ocean protocol human
protocol idx and a ton of other projects
so we're really excited about the
ecosystem that we're building
and it's just truly amazing to see the
progress that we've made
made over the past weeks
and i think the most exciting part for
me today about this presentation is to
show you guys the balance your demo that
we've
prepared so basically uh as you've heard
me
say before a balancer is coming to
moonbeam and we wrote a blog post about
it you can see it
on this link on the in the slide and uh
what i'm gonna show you today
is a demo a demo proof of concept so
basically uh we really worked hard on
providing
uh on bringing all the smart contracts
from balancer to moonbeam
making sure to adapt their front end so
we had some some help with parity uh
and some cases but it was truly amazing
to see you know bring in the bouncer
to to moonbeam so we have a very uh a
proof of concept
demo that will show the core
functionalities uh also including the
smart order routing
uh which is basically the the tool that
it's used to to
maximize or get you the best price
possible when you're doing trade sub
tokens
uh if you have time we'll i'll show you
the pool management
ui which is uh something related to
you can create pools and and do other
stuff and
we're also looking for a long-term
support uh meaning that uh
we're looking for developers or teams
that maintain balancer on moonbeam
uh this means that there are grants that
are being issued both
by balancer and moonbeam and you can
find more information in the link that
it's uh
it's uh basically on the on the slide
so yeah uh for this demo uh what i want
to do now it's it's basically to explain
you a little bit of the uh
of the pools that we've deployed uh to
moonbeam
so uh basically we have deployed uh we
don't have the graph fully working right
now on our test net
although we're actually trying to to
bring this this feature set
to to moonbase alpha soon so we have to
plot we have actually
we've actually um deployed some students
some amount of pools
with some token allocations and the
pools already uh
right so let's just say for example pool
one
so in the case of pool 1 we have a 33
distribution weight
and we have actually said for example uh
rap 8 we have deposited 100
rap each 200 token ones so these are
erc20 tokens
and 300 uh token twos in pool 2 what
we've done is
do a 25 distribution in weight and we've
actually
uh done uh 100 wrap each 200 300
and 400 and on uh and we have other
pools
i'm not going to go through like the
math or anything but the idea is that we
have pre-deployed a certain amount of
pools with tokens allocated so we can
trade with them right
and don't go into the math here because
you can probably arbitrage
the crap out of these pools but it's
just for demo purposes
so i'm going to go ahead and
jump to the demo that i prepared for you
guys so
this is basically the balancer front one
one of the balancers front and
that you can see here i have connected
it to a moonbeam node
and you can see that i have metamask
being used as an injected provider here
and what i have here is an account that
holds
different amount of tokens and i'm gonna
for example show you guys
what happens when i do a trade between
rap eath and token 2
so if i just put here two tokens you
will see that i get the price
information and if i expand this menu
right here
you can see that the smart order routing
is optimizing my trade
by using two balancer pools so this is
really great to see here
um if i for example choose to trade
rap eth versus token three i'm gonna put
here
five you will see that once again the
smart order routing that actually works
off chain
is optimizing my trade with these two
balancer pools
but if i increase this uh this right
here
you will see that now the smart aura
routing is
including another pull into the party
right so it's great to see how this you
know this trade is being optimized to to
give you the user the best price
possible
and now what i can do is it's go ahead
and let's let's do this swap right so i
have
500 right wrap ease and 300 uh token
threes
and i'm going to go ahead and click swap
so
as you would expect in in in ethereum
metamask will pop
up saying that you know you want to sign
this transaction
and you can see that i have a grasp gas
price set to zero and this is because
this is tested
and i can just click confirm and the
trade is being done you can see here the
spinning loading interface and you can
see now that i have
450 rap eth and i have 150 more
token threes and the cool thing is now
the smart order router is actually
telling me now that the
the pool the trade if you do this trade
again
the the the pool allocation will be
different for to maximize and optimize
this this trade
so i think this is really cool and
really uh amazing to show you guys
balancer working on moonbeam
another ui that i prepared for you guys
is this pool management ui
so right now like i mentioned we don't
have the graph working
on on moonbase alpha but hopefully in
the next
weeks we'll have an instance of balance
or sub graphs working
because this information is fed by the
balancer subgraph
so i mean this information that you see
right here is currently on ethereum
mainnet
but other functionalities of this of
this web ui
actually works you can wrap some for
example eve
i can just i have actually i have i have
450 so before i do this
let me reload this page
so you can see that i have 450 wrap each
i'm gonna
deposit 50 each for example
and one this this once this trade is
confirmed and this page will reload the
balance you should see that i have
i'll have 500 e wrap each down here
hopefully it reloads in time
if not i'll just reload this way web
page
there you go i have uh 500 rapies now
i can also create a pool to create a
pool i first have to set up a proxy if
you're familiar with balancer
so i'll just go ahead and set up my
proxy contract
and so once the proxy contract is set up
so the proxy contract is how you
interact with the balancer pools
so i can click next and just add the
amount of tokens that i want to add to
my pool right so i can add for example
uh let's put fifty percent in in uh wrap
each and i'll put 100 in amount
25 percent token one i'm not really sure
about the amounts i should set but
this is just for demo purposes right
oops
and then basically if i approve the
proxy as an expender in this erc 20
tokens
i'll just set up a swap 3 for example
and i can just
click this warning message and just
create i cannot do it right now because
i have to
you know approve the proxy as an
expander but for the purpose of the demo
we wanted to show you guys this proof of
concept and like i mentioned before uh
we're working we're looking for teams to
actually uh take this
long term and and and support this
deployment of balancer in mumbai's alpha
long term and their
their grants being issued by both
balancer and and moonbeam right
so yeah i mean this that's it from my
presentation thanks a lot i hope you
like the demo
and now i'll be joined by the sushi swap
team so we have joe
at the cto and warren crypto the the
lead architect of bento box that they're
gonna present their demo that is running
on boom based alpha
thanks a lot guys
what's going on all right hi joe
hey um i'm actually gonna change up my
video real fast all right
doesn't seem to be responding okay
uh
i hope that's not the right button
either okay whatever let's roll uh
this is my it's my no my video is back
off
okay they're cool yeah no all right
sweet
okay all right guys take it away
sure so uh i'm gonna share my screen
here
and show you kind of like first of all
um we we deployed to moon beams test at
moon base
um and we're
from the standpoint that um
uh
moonbeam came to us it was out of time
hey do you mind going on uh thank you
cool uh it came to us a time when
um uh sushi was
you know kind of like in a downturn um
nobody wanted to work with us and
uh moonbeam was a team that reached out
to
a make a sushi deployment on moonbeam
so like uh moonbeam is kind of a
project that's you know close to us
we have already deployed to moonbase and
um and we're going to do a swap and add
and then remove
uh just like anything else um
uh we're going to uh swap
uh we're
[Music]
confirm and
you know there's always like that kind
of like that that time in between from
when you get swapped
clearing
all right there we go swapped
uh yeah
[Music]
it's choppy uh
okay
i did have some issues with my audio as
well so i don't know if it's we broke
crowdcast like we did on the encoded
presentation or what's going on but
let me see temporarily
okay yeah uh is my is my audio working
out
it's still a little choppy
maybe maybe i turn my video off is it
better
i think that's better okay cool just let
me know if it
like interrupt me if it starts uh
becoming a problem
yeah video frozen yeah okay cool cool
yeah it must be like my downlink or
whatever yeah um
did uh what did we miss did we miss the
swap
the whole demo oh the whole demo worked
great okay cool
so all right so now we're networking yo
you can't see your screen
okay cool this is
i swear i tested this before i started
um
that's just boring okay uh
not really any controls here for the
screen sharing anymore if you hover over
here
i see i see yeah sorry
okay cool can we see the screens now
there you go yep
right we were able to see the swapper
nope
um we'll do a max here
and and we'll supply that
the um the uh
we're adding these two token pairs into
a liquidity pool and this is part of the
amm design
right um an amm design is basically a
forced buyer seller
um to provide liquidity for the market
hence liquidity provider
um or lp tokens right so we're minting
lp tokens by being both sides of the
trade oh
dang this stinks all right cool
um so anyway so there we go it's
confirmed
uh we have added the liquidity it's now
in
in the pool um and we'll do a remove
let's do a remove we gotta
uh do an approve ah very nice
we did a we implemented approves yeah
okay cool there we go
um and uh wait for that to
go through and then we're done
[Music]
i was told that there would be a bit of
lag on the test net today
and i think that that is really good
feedback because it definitely is
there we go mine great okay cool so yeah
that's the demo
we're able to swap add remove liquidity
we're already deployed on moonbeam so
create your test tokens and like
integrate um in the way that you think
that you'll integrate when we go to
mainnet because we're going to mainnet
as well um
and we have like a pretty good i think
um
plan for you know the mainnet launch
can't wait for you guys to see it
all right
cool uh let me figure this out
sorry about that
all right um so i'm going to talk about
the bento box today
um that we deployed on uh moonbeam um
deployment was very easy
um just with hardhead like any evm
compatible chain we had no problems with
that which is very nice
um so the bento box is basically um
it's kind of like a token fault and you
can just load your tokens into it so
here
you can see i have some token balances
and i also have some tokens in the bento
box and
this kind of shows um whether i i have a
proof this or not so
here you can if you open this up you can
see this hasn't been approved yet
um so if i want i can approve this all
and after that i can move tokens um i've
already put some
some sushi tokens in here um
so they're they're sitting in my bento
box now
and um so the bento box is a token fold
that
many people can build protocols on top
of so
um kashi the lending platform will be
one of the first things that
we will deploy on it but for the demo
today
i've got a sort of a simpler example of
a
salaries less fasting
feed that you can create so we'll go
ahead and do that
so
let's say in the next 30 minutes we're
gonna fast
some sushi thousands we see
and we're going to create this
okay i guess we're not going to create
it
anyway i already created some some
salaries here that you can see
maybe just to refresh the page there we
go that's why
all right let's do that again
and
so that should um create a new new
salary
and it's using the funds from the bento
box so it will use the funds from here
and so obviously
why would you use another wallet or
token fold
and the reason is yields so
the whole point of d5 you know we don't
want better yields
and so what the bento box does is any
tokens that are sitting in there that
are idle
can create yields in the background so
if we
have a look here we will see that
there's actually
a strategy attached to this this token
so 88 of these tokens are automatically
invested into
a strategy that creates yield in this
case it's using the
sushi bar and for that for
to show this for demo purposes
i have
created so this is the bar there is some
stuff sitting in there
and what we can do is we can
just donate some money into that
so normally this would be through actual
profit from the from the system
but that part is not running out
just wait till that comes in
and here we see our salary that's been
that's that's uh has been created
and so what you can see here this is now
a thousand sushi that i've just looked
up
um that's gonna be fasting in the next
30 minutes
so normally that would just be dead
tokens that are not not working same as
in the banter box here i have
98 000 sitting there it's not doing
anything
but now you can see if i actually
harvest
the strategy
then the benefits from the strategy will
be applied to
any protocol any tokens that have a
strategy in any protocol built on top of
that will benefit from that
just wait till that goes through
and here we can see we've got now more
sushi that is that is sitting there
fasting
and our balance here has gone up as well
so even while your tokens are
doing something let's say they're eating
sitting in an amm
or sitting in a landing platform if it's
built on top of the bento box
you're getting extra yields both through
flash loans and through strategies
and this is all running live on on the
modern beam test net right now
cool well that's it for me
okay uh so that is the demo
welcome back to another mining chamber
video in this video i'm going to show
you how to effectively use your main pc
sorry
it's also playing all right so uh
that is the demo and uh
actually we call we call the project as
a confidential confidentiality layer for
polka dot ecosystem
and unlike other uh blockchains we serve
as an
infrastructure in the uh powertrain
ecosystem
instead of like instead of
being a standalone platform to run
something
we intend to serve other blockchains
so uh i
just also introduced uh myself a little
bit i'm hung
uh and i'm from fellow network i'm the
co-founder
and lead developer so
uh what is the so why we call it
confidentiality layer
uh so if you are if you are familiar
with
the smart contract and blockchain you
know that
everything on blockchain is actually
transparent
because this is how blockchain work we
need consensus
we need to replica of the data over the
network to make sure
the data can be trusted can be trusted
and verified
and this creates a problem because
everything on the blockchain is
transparent
so if you want to store something secret
and you want to store some user privacy
data
it will become a problem for us so
instead of
running the smart contract right on the
blockchain
we use a technology called trusted
execution environment
so it's an insulated area in the cpu
so actually it's also called hardware
secure enclave because it's a
combination of hardware
and software so uh we can deploy some
program
in the te in the enclave so
uh because it's isolated from the other
parts
in the system so even if you have the
control over
the operating system or you even have
the physical access
to the computer you still cannot
manipulate the data
inside you cannot access the data
inside the enclave and of course the ram
is also encrypted
so it's end-to-end encrypted
so what about we run the smart contract
in the enclave so for example if we put
a token contract
into the secure enclave it turns into a
privacy token
so you you can send some token to others
but you cannot be besides
uh the the sender and the receiver
nobody else
can see the amount the sender and the
receiver
of the the transaction of course we can
also like put some
nft inside the secure enclave so we can
make like
loot box and if we put the unislab
uh contract inside the enclave we can
make it a dark pool
and also like we can also use the
secure enclave to protect the position
for some derivatives like some lending
protocol
or option protocol so
how we make it uh how do we make it
happen
so uh what we what we have is something
called confidential contract it's
very similar to a regular smart contract
as and as you can see here we have a
very simple
demo uh this is a hello world contract
it only have a counter and we have a
commands which is just like transactions
you send transaction to the blockchain
to invoke the command
and in this uh in this
sample it supports increment the counter
by some amount
so far is very similar to regular
contract
but uh what is uh different
is that the the intermediate state the
input the output is all
encrypted so in order to query the
contract you cannot just
pull the data from the blockchain
because it's encrypted
so instead of uh instead of that
what we should do is to define the query
acquirer is
very similar to when you like you are
building a backhand
and you accept some requests from the
clients right
so uh inside the query you can actually
check the credential of the requesters
uh for example in this uh sample
uh the first line of the contract we
check
if the sender is the root account so if
it's not a root account
we can return an arrow not authorized
and if you are root account then we can
reply with with the actual account
read from the contract so in this way
actually we protect the privacy and
we can we make it very flexible for the
developers
to define which data can be accessed
outside
the smart contract and which data is
protected
inside the confidential smart contract
of course
one thing to mention is that now this is
showing our native
rust contract and in the future we are
going to switch to
inc smart contract very soon
uh so that is one part is the smart
contract
but how do we provide the
confidentiality to other projects
so the way is used by using xcmp
so like is showing in this uh diagram
on file network we can have multiple
secure enclaves
running the smart contract and they are
heterogeneous
actually so we we don't deploy all the
contracts
on uh on all the secure enclaves
but instead we can deploy uh like if we
have
100 uh secure enclave so in theory we
can we can
we can run 100 smart contracts at the
same time
and in this way we can have a very high
throughput
but it also creates a problem that is
how this
smart contract can communicate
with each other so the answer is using
xcmp
so from the beginning we have this
we we have the compat uh compatibility
with xcmp
in our mind when we started the project
so all the way to interact with the
smart contract
is through xampp so of course
uh we can let other smart contracts on
other blockchains to invoke the
confidential smart contract on phala
network
so like here is the first uh uh here
it is a deep dive of the of the demo we
just show
in this uh in this presentation
which is secret assets we also call it
called secret wallets
so in secret wallet so any part chain
can send their
token to our blockchain and we
uh we will uh save the balance
in inside the secure enclave so in this
way
all the trans as long as you convert
some token
from other blockchains to our secret
wallet
and then you cannot order like all the
transferring all the transactions is
invisible
from the blockchain and
uh under the hood uh so here we
uh we we are showing uh what happened
under the hood so like in the demo we
showed that
we can send some a color token to file
our network
secret secret wallet so the first thing
is to invoke
the transfer function on the akala side
and here we
show that this is actually actually an
xcm
uh an xcm sent to a power channel 13
which is file network so actually xcm
has two parts one parse uh the first
part is the message itself it defines
uh how the message will uh
so what what the message is is
describing
and uh the second part is the effects it
describes what we'll do
when we receive this message so uh when
we transfer some token from a color
uh the the message we created is called
withdraw
assets because you will first withdraw
some token from your
own account and deposit it into the
reserved account
uh which is the uh which is controlled
by file network
and then after the deposit is
already there we can also uh
in we can also trigger more effects
happening
on the other blockchains so uh
when the transfer is done on the color
side there will be a hrmp
message uh from a color to local
and uh by uh and and through xcm
executor on the local side uh it will
also
it will uh redirect the the message from
local code
to file a network so this parts
an upstream upward message and a
downward message
combined together is called is the
regular
hrmp but uh unlike other blockchains
we don't want to build everything on our
blockchain but instead we want to
uh we want to serve the other
blockchains
by using our confidential smart contract
so
the end point is actually not the uh
not valid network the blockchain but
the confidential smart contract so on
fire network what we have is not the
end point but an xcm rotor
the rotor will redirect the message
received from other power chains and
dispatch it to the actual secure enclave
who ran the
secret wallet so we call this an ingress
message
and the actual endpoint is contract
assets
uh and this is the this is not the uh
the the the assets pallets uh on
uh substrate side this is the
this is the the confidential version
inside the te enclave
yeah so what we received is a message
called deposit assets
and the xcm comes from project 666
which is a color and the destination
is uh is an account a in the
in in the file network uh
space so uh actually when you send some
token from
uh one person to another project you can
specify
you can send send the token from your
own account
to uh also your own account but on
another blockchain but you can also
specify some other accounts
for sure and
uh we call this off chain hrm
just just to let you know we've only got
about a minute or two for this section
okay okay i will be very quick so yeah
so uh this is the uh this is uh we call
this off-chain hrmp
and of course uh the the the in the
uh reversed direction we can also
send an egress message to withdraw some
token from our side and
pass it directly to the akala site to
send the token back yeah so we were
going to launch the
uh the secret network on local kobe 1
in mid-march and
that is a simple uh use case we can also
combine the different
uh the different uh uh utilities and
different power chains together for
example like
if there is a zero knowledge uh power
change to protect the token privacy
we can combine them together with us and
we can run a
decentralized exchange on the final
network side because
uh the dax is more complicated than than
token and
and it's very hard to use zero knowledge
proof to protect it
yeah so that's all from my side yeah so
uh we are going to launch a series of
products
in the near future and if you are
interested feel free to
like reach out to us on telegram you can
also check our
uh open source code on github thank you
very much
cool yeah let's get it started so i'm
going to talk about plasma network and
what we are doing right now so our
mission is to make dao surprising
network is community delivery margin
change smart contract platform on
polkadot
so why crazy network plasma network is a
multi-battery machine ducks hub on
polkadot that support ethereum
and the data solution so what do you
mean by
multi-battery machines so we support
both ethereum virtual machine
and web assembly so you can deploy
solidity contract
by by contract on the top of ethereum
battery machine today
by using the mix metamask truffle
ecdss signature or whatever and
you can deploy ink contract on the top
of our assembly
in the yeah we are also implementing
zika lola
so why scaling solution for polkadot
polkadot is also a scaling solution so
this is a really good question
i think is many ethereum projects will
use
a lot of you know load up solution
and then um it's going to be easy for
them to migrate
from ethereum to polkadot space without
compromising roll up solution
because we have low laps on the
topography network
so plasma networks make it easy to
create
launch and use steps and the
actually we have been working on zika
lola and the 50 percent is done
and it's under the review by website
foundation right now
so far we have been building on polka
dots since 2019
and the about our huge milestone in 2021
is to become sama para chain as well as
forgot of parachain
and we have been working on mercy
bachelor muslim
israeli bachelor machine and web
assembly both only
one and layer two so you can deploy any
sort of contract on the top of layer one
as well as there two
so if you are uh interested in cheaper
gas or faster finality or flexible apps
developments
so you can deploy dabs on the top of
rear two
but also you can deploy it up on the top
of layer one
and they also that the huge difference
between plasma network and the
other project is doubts taking i'm going
to talk about upstaking radar
and this is our technical achievements
we became the
power chain and we deployed a smart
contract on the top of
our test net power chain and the i think
tomorrow
or day after tomorrow i'm going we are
going to support ethereum battery
machine
so you can deploy solidity contract or
bypass contract on the topo polka dot
test net power chain
instead of independent chain or isolate
data chain so this is gonna be very huge
you know upgrade for us
yeah and also we are making bridges like
ethereum bridges
and secret network bridge and finance
smart chain bridge
so humans will be talking about secret
network bridge data
yeah uh and last week uh we have done
xcmep con uh transaction between acara
and
brazen so interpretability was possible
but it became reality
so we are going to work with inter a and
other projects to make
crochet messaging passing happen
yeah and also i'm going to talk about
our new
yeah portal
so this is the ui and the anyone can
create dabs
by yes through this plus network portal
all you have to do is you have to
specify account
and they fill out your you know website
and figure out your name
and the you know category it can be
defined it can be you know power change
it can be
oracle it can be gaming and also the
last things is to upload
um web assembly contract or solidity
contract here
and then sorry it's not interactive but
we are going to launch it in weeks
then let's say chain link deploy oracle
on the top of
the network the logo will be shown here
and the yeah prm token holder can stay
they are talking not only on network
like
staking but also on dubs so let's say
let's say um unisoft join the plaza
network
so prepare a token holder can stake they
are talking about uni swap
by doing so you are supporting uni swap
and the unicef the better offer parking
um
token on prm token this means
uh by making dubs on the top of plaza
network you can get prm token
and it will be tradable when we discover
this is gonna be simple but there is
strong incentive for developer
and the i think we got a question
regarding uh
lockdrop and we are also making the
interface
so you can join our lock drop during the
the project auction through plus network
portal
so you can specify dot amount then you
can get premium token if you deposit
dots for us
to become a power chain
core and the infuser will be talking
about
yeah bridges in the we are working on
secret network bridge
in syrian bridge and banana small chain
bridge uh we got fund
from finance and the okay x so we have
our incentive to make a bridges
yeah and the ecosystem is getting bigger
and bigger and bigger
and the auto team joined our plaza
network projects
and we are going to launch grants
program there is soon so it will be
great if you could deploy it apps on the
top operating network
and i will leave it to himself
all right thank you soda for passing uh
let's just go through the in-depth of
the
bridge contract that we're trying to
make right now so
here's the uh bridge contract between
the secret
um so this is basically i mean i cannot
go through the whole code but
this is basically about this um like a
multi-sig bridge
where it when it executes the
transaction
then it just sends it the
multisig bridge detects the txid and
then
signs those like uh transactions sends
to a secret
so uh you can add those like owners and
then
fee collectors for this bridge transfer
and you can also add those tokens uh let
me show you some work throughs so
let's just say that it's just a poc
though but let's just say you want to
deploy a token
uh and then probably compile it in a
test net like
here below like uh let's just say the
initial supply is like
1 million or something and then go with
the test
and then test this one should be 18.
so once you deploy it
you have the token pending uh once it's
deployed
uh you get the token address from your
dabs it could be your governance token
or it could be some other erc20 like
peck tokens or whatever
then you just add the token to the
bridge
wait the minimum amount is like the
minimum amount to stake
so transact
and once those tokens are on the bridge
it will be available to move around this
ui
in a bridge like this so basically uh
we're trying to include
our own plasm and erc20 tokens
such as like from the dabs or it could
be other
wrapped pocket asset tokens such as
akala
vala or other other rap tokens uh we're
trying to put that between the secret
and then secret will send those like
tokens from ibc
such as like tara it could be other like
secret
secret or secret tether and then it will
move around
with the secret build the script secret
[ __ ]
built with built with the multi-sig
operators such as
from like b harvest and the other
multi-sig operator as well so this is
basically how
our multi-stick bridge will work i hope
you guys build
that and then let your assets to move
around in heterogeneous
blockchains such as cosmos polka dot and
also binance chain
thank you you know they find this all
about covering decentralized finance
wherever that may be
so if it's thriving on polka dot i think
you know i
will probably see more and more polka
dot based d5 coverage
on on the defiant as well okay so um it
looks like we we have
our our panelists on board um
great uh so there's our retail from
akala lucas from centrifuge and aiden
um from snowfort um
[Music]
welcome and um excited to chat about
uh about d5 with you guys about what
you're seeing
on um the the future of uh polka dots
um ecosystem
but first um as i was looking uh
or listening to your very impressive
demos um i always had the question of
like
when um so can you kind of just clarify
exactly what people can do
uh with your your apps right now i know
there's like
alpha betas and like different greek
letters but like
are people like can people go and test
uh yeah if we you can go through
um the different kind of phases of
development that uh your
your different applications and projects
are all right so uh retail can
can you start oh yeah can can you hear
me all right
yeah okay awesome so um for arcola we
pretty much already have the test net
running for the past five months
so everything that we demo can be
accessible today
about the key question about when like
when will we go live
on kusama or when we go live on polka
dots
well it all depends on the actual
project and functionality
and from the experience we're working
with with the substrate team with some
prosperity i think it will be ready when
whatever is ready so
uh we are all hopeful that you're gonna
be released soon but we also hope for
that um
for the release it's going to be safe
and smooth so
i think it's getting close i don't have
a definitive date but i think you will
be ready when it's ready
all right okay um i guess like
this this all depends on uh when
like polka dot and and the pertains
launch itself but you're saying that
when that happens then akala will be
will be ready to go basically yeah and
and i think there will be um
notice there will be announcement from
either um alcala or from officially from
pogada or from parity
um to let the world know that now the
power chain option is coming because
this is the unbounding periods that we
will
um the people have to unbound their
token to support power chains so
um i don't think that there needs to be
rush or that this should be like a date
that we need to set but when it's coming
we all
we will always be notified um
accordingly
okay when when do you expect um
to have to have this like very chain
option happen i know you said like
there's no
specific date but is this like a matter
of do you guys know a matter of like
weeks or or months or anyone have like
an idea
um i think we can all guess i think
ideon
and luke as we can all guess but my um
i think we're getting close on kusama i
mean that's not
[Laughter]
i available in a way we are we already
are ready
um we so i alluded it in in the demo but
like we
have been building on ethereum to
like three years ago uh made the
decision actually to work on substrate
builds build out
way before pulpit went live i think it
was
um it was march of last year um that we
went
live with our mainnet and so our mainnet
today is actually
um an almost identical copy of polkadot
so same consensus mechanism
no relay chains of course or we're just
an independent state chain but
um so we have that and and sort of
like for us like the pieces there's a
small part of our infrastructure that is
running on that chain it's how
the different loans are originated and
then investors sort of
use uh tin lake on ethereum because
that's where the liquidity is that's
where all the the dfa ecosystem is today
so we sort of have this
hybrid approach today of our own chain
and um
and ethereum we have our own bridge uh
for that
um and as far chains become available
when they're big when they become
available
um that is something that um of course
we're very excited to
to start using but it doesn't really um
hinder us from using
using uh sort of our tech already
yep i think um now 4.6 million
die in like loans outstanding from
different
um uh borrowers and uh like have
a ton of users growing every day in on
ethereum
right um yeah i guess yeah i know uh
centrifuge is like what i i meant will
it be ready to go on polka dot as as
soon as it's
yeah yeah so we're on the latest
uh version of substrate in our test net
we have
our main nets slightly behind but this
is something we're working on cha cha
cha is what we're using to test
a lot of integration but yeah i guess as
um
as power chain options will go live
we'll be able to take basically our
runtime that we have today that's tested
and running in production and
and sort of deploy that cool
all right and um aidan how about for you
yeah so we're pretty much in a similar
position to to the others
we are expecting to be pretty much ready
to launch at the same time that power
change launch
and so we're kind of waiting on parity
for that there are a few differences um
our power chain
does require some new functionality that
doesn't really exist on
polka dots test night yet and so we're
kind of using a custom branch
uh we do expect that functionality to be
merged into
like main required contest net and
eventually polka dot at the same time
as prior change and so when everyone
eventually converges to
production uh we'll be there at start um
but
um we are kind of blocked on that and
and so we have like an internal test
nets
we're planning to launch a public-facing
demo in the next few weeks
um but in terms of like production
assets and real world efforts from
ethereum
there it only happened whenever parrot
parodies ready with power chains
okay cool um and so you you all expect
to have your own paritanes on polka dot
is that right yeah yeah okay
um and so my question on on peritones um
is especially for d5 because
interoperability has
proven to be so key on ethereum d5
this concept of money legos um
does it work in exactly the same way
with
uh dabs built on different paritains
like is interoperability as seamless as
um applications being built on the same
exact
layer one i would say that um there's no
fundamental
areas to preventing that seamlessness so
like one minor difference
is that when um someone if someone's
using a dab on one power chain
that is interacting with adapt on
another chain that interaction happens
asynchronously
and so um instead of like there being a
single atomic transaction like you would
have on ethereum
there may be two transactions but that's
more kind of a technical thing
um if you look at the user experience of
say using ethereum you're waiting
for like a minute or longer for
confirmation times and for things to
happen anyway
and so when multiple power chains are
interacting with each other
the amount of time that it takes for
these um
multi-atomic transactions to happen will
likely still be faster than if you were
to just wait for a single ethereum
transaction
and so i don't really see there being ux
compromises it's more kind of on the
technical side and the way that
developers
have to think about things that change i
think that
i always use this analogy and you
brought up async right i always
use this analogy like when you build the
website 20 years
ago you created your like one php file
and it
pulled everything together and like
served you then this website
and you would load one request from the
from the server and you get all you need
and that's sort of like ethereum today
right you submit your transaction
everything happens atomically
um and it's great it's easy um but it
doesn't scale and
for the same reasons like when you go to
a website today actually
there's probably 30 different things
that happen in the background which are
also asynchronous
transactions but in the end you end up
with that same website being rendered
right and there's a bit of
composition and so um like
d5 will look for from an engineering
perspective radically different
um under the hood but yeah i think i
agree on the usability that can be
um very similar and and even on ethereum
right like you see
the l2 space will have exactly the same
issues
and so i think we're like it's going to
be um it's just not going to be a
reality anymore that most of these
things will happen synchronously
like you'll jump from l1 to l2 and from
one chain to another
and protocols and users will learn how
to use it how to
implement that stuff
um yeah retail there uh something to add
yeah i think that's a great an analogy
by by lucas uh it's like it
you feel like um the current um
ethereum.evm application
is like a mainframe computer and we are
moving slowly towards like the
server age which like each um
specialized networks
is on its own server and um we can see
this is like different approach um to
solve the same problem our theory on
this layer too
unpopular this project and i think
that's exactly why this uh technical
working group are formed
as a community driven tech tech uh group
of like
we need to find at least like the token
can be circulating freely
between all the different projects so we
have a an
interface to talk with each other so i
think that is like the very beginning of
the compostability that we can already
see
i do believe in further development down
into the
poker developments we can see richer
compatibility for example a power chair
might decide to expose
some of its core functionality through
the xcm that means for example a project
might decide to expose
the attacks or in centrifuge cases might
expose their
characterization or their financial
assets through xcm pandora
so that can be also be composable as
well but for now i think the bare
minimum is that the token is already
circulating and that's great
okay so um different tokens issued on
different pertains
can like easily circulate on other
proteins even though they have
they may have different parameters and
be built on on different ways
they can still kind of like interconnect
with
with different applications there yeah
and i think on powerchain it's more of
like a diplomatic relationship between
different projects because they are
soviet network
it's just a very easy to build up
relationship um
and and have this value transfer in a
trustless way
and i think now in the past there's like
the spree um
at the sp ie environment so project can
actually talk to other projects
without going through the relation and
that's where i think the most
scalable interpretation communication
gonna happen
okay so something like urine which is
basically like a yield bouncer between
like dozens of different ethereum defy
apps and it's just like it it needs to
to connect to and plug into all these
different apps
that would still be possible on on polka
dot d5
i think so and i i wouldn't um discount
the possibility that is
going to be like an aggregator approach
and that's going to harvest all the
different rewards from different
projects for example centrifuge has a
money market
um this financial instrument that can be
um can be can be harvested
um with the snowfall bridge there could
be like ethereum
yield that can be harvested so there
might be um down in the past of
development
cool um lucas i i i'm wondering
about a team's building like you on on
a polka dot and other things like
ethereum is there a concern about
fragmenting
um liquidity like does it make sense to
build on different chains
or will do you think um
teams would consolidate on one chain in
the long run
so that's a really good question i don't
i i think
the one the one like obviously fragment
liquidity is bad
we want to avoid that um it also though
is very easy
to move liquidity around and actually
like you just mentioned urine right like
that
that's all they're doing and you can you
can do that very easily
for us like sort of how we think about
our like our ecosystem is
we have two different two fundamentally
different kinds of users we have the
asset originators that bring these real
world assets on chain
they use our our power chain to create
these
assets investors then that will invest
and earn earn interest on these assets
they
don't necessarily need to be on
centrifuge chain they can do
um they might be a maker on ethereum
they might
be on a caller like it might be
collateral somewhere
um or who knows right and so for us how
we think about
fragmentation and interoperability is
like like we want
these investors to be wherever we ever
necessary and we make it as easy to move
these tokens
on the acid originator side that's like
sort of the heavy usage like a lot of
the very specific
interaction that we need happens right
it's not just a simple
erc20 token transfer fungible token
transfer and so that's sort of how we
split
it up um and how we think about like
avoiding this
like fragmentation okay yeah like
i would say to add to that the problem
of fragmentation of liquidity is not
really
a cross-chain problem like even if you
look at ethereum there's multiple
protocols and
default applications where liquidity has
really become fragmented and so whether
that fragmentation happens across chains
or across protocols or
across people and communities um it's
kind of a
more general uh conversation around how
do we join and
separate liquidity whether on the
technical level that happens on
different chains or different protocols
i think it's more of like a kind of
technical implementation detail rather
than
uh financial product consideration
sure um what are some some of the
incentives that that you think will be
used in polka dot d5 to bring over
liquidity from
from ethereum and um i don't know like
snowfall as the bridge is uh obviously
key in making this happen in in getting
liquidity from
kind of the biggest d5 ecosystem right
now
are you thinking of of having incentives
for people
uh to put their tokens over or same for
for a cal and centrifuge yeah so
i mean we're going to have incentives
that make it easy for people to put
their tokens over
but we're not currently planning to have
additional incentives
to specifically entice people to bring
their tokens over i think that will come
more from
the being enticed by other power chains
and other kind of protocols
for example if there's your nakala or
yodan centrifuge um our links to
alkaline centrifuge and other chains
will be uh pathways from ethereum into
them and so
essentially we uh we're kind of counting
on them
to entice people to deliver demand into
the polkadot ecosystem
right yeah i can echo that so i mean we
will definitely have some form of
incentive when we launch the network and
we will also able to direct the
incentive to where it's most needed for
example if we think i'm more ethereum
assets need to be crossed
and that's the beauty of like this
composable network right so we can say
that hey
um we can provide incentive on making
new uh snowys
or we can provide a new incentive on
creating
a long position using yeast um so all
depends on where the demands is we think
it's going to
um to hit so well this is like the
beautiful of like have
one consumer focus application that has
a bridge that we can work together
and make this is like as frictionless
and as um as
useful for all for the trade as possible
um
so you're farming on anakala
well i wouldn't call that uh yeah it
will be similar but
there will be actual um more meaningful
product out of alkaline
i think there's like um after eu farming
i think the staking dealership um
gam is going to have a very heavy play
um the actual
dot has u built-in so we have some very
interesting product that we might be
able to introduce once we go live
or revolving around the actual staking
rewards
um so for for early traders tap into the
system not only they will be earnings
for example um
um incentive on the on the network token
they might also tap into the
uh the rewarding part of the actual pls
network like dot rewards kusama reward
um and if you if you put those into play
that is actually very very interesting
oh interesting okay um cool and
uh lucas for you like how how do you
think uh
you'll incentivize people to use uh
centrifuge and polka dot
i mean right now it costs around
100 or more for one of our asset
originators to originate alone
um i think is that's already a pretty
strong incentive to
not use ethereum um i mean
in the end like the yield farming you
have to watch out there it doesn't
become a bit of a race to the bottom
it's
i think a very interesting way to start
a community and there can be a way that
like as a community you decide um
where you want to direct attention and
that i think is
is super valuable um but but ultimately
like
i believe the usability that polka dot
can offer
and the the transaction costs are going
to be
what will drive a lot of it um another
thing right is just
um polka dot itself the the activity the
market cap like the the purity
just the amounts of liquidity in this
whole ecosystem
are now already so big that um i think
this can be like a viable
um a very viable like early pool of
liquidity and users
i mean it's the top top five
you know top ten uh how many where are
they right now
um so it's and that is like that can
start right and it's and i think sort of
if you start with that then
um liquidity will find its way right
like if we see something about d5 it's
like
there's hardly any um any free lunch
left on that
anything free left on the table so you
can you'll see
like money flowing where there's like
cheap transactions scalability
uh liquidity and so i i would focus on
that
um as opposed to too much of like
subsidizing it
oh yeah yeah
we're seeing it with like finance chain
um finance martin people going there
even though it's not
necessarily kind of the most
decentralized
etc but of course like money talks smart
cheap transactions matter um
so okay so going looking
um forward and and seeing where define
on polka dot is heading where do you see
this ecosystem
um being at the end of the year like how
how how big do you think it would be how
many
applications um do you think it will be
comparable to what is happening on
ethereum today i mean
do you see uh something like tvl on
polka dot overtaking
ethereum's tbl by the end of the year
um i don't i don't think um you will be
grown
at that scale but i do think there's
some something that unique will be
created in the polkadot ecosystem
uh with one project um connectable um
composable with other projects
i think we're able to see something
that's very very unique for example
on the fallout team demonstrate like a
privacy layer so we can start to see
like
one project asset and teleport it to the
path harvest layer and become a privacy
asset
so i think that's something that's super
interesting and that might be the
the new possibility that we can start to
see i i do expect the polkadots
ecosystem grow um and grow fast but i
i really don't think um at a scale that
maybe by the end of the
day the yeah that we can take over but
the thing is that it's like
um at the point i see it is that this
whole movement this whole
decentralized finance movement is very
very early on right so there's like
a huge growing pie for what i i'm gonna
be honest i think it's gonna
replace the whole financial sector so we
are still in a very early stage
and each one of us working on this
sector is just like
uh reinforcing this idea or pushing this
idea to the world so
in that sense um i i would see that i'd
rather to see that we grow together
rather than say hey it's taking over or
something like that
i agree um yeah
aiden what are your thoughts on kind of
long term for
or end of the year at least for a
defiant polka dot
yeah i mean i'm not going to make like
predictions about
uh whether or not i think ethereum's
going to take over i think it's very
unlikely
but i do think that like as soon as
power chains are launched and
within two or three months of people
starting to connect to each other
there'll be like
uh a lot of flow happening between
polkadot and ethereum and
a lot of flow moving across power chains
and so um
i i imagine that like maybe not in terms
of tvo um
like overtaking ethereum but in terms of
kind of transactions and usage and
like people playing with things i could
imagine um it's scaling
like pretty quickly in that sense
interesting
because when i make your for your
predictions
i mean maybe the one prediction i do i
will make it as well but
i i expect power change to be live by
then but maybe
to come back to your first question but
uh no i um
i would say yeah i
i think sort of boring of like alex i'm
like
every long crypto bed i've made in my
life i've probably been wrong about so i
don't want to say too much but
the thing i have seen is sort of the def
like the d5 ecosystem in in ethereum
developing
was and i think it's really important
was
accelerated by like just the whole
community coming around the euroc20
token
and it sort of happened naturally and we
had this like
suddenly this number of tokens after the
2017 ico boom that people started doing
things with and experimenting with
and it still took um then like from 2018
to 2019 and they sort of
started growing and like last summer it
was like really exploding and
it's been going ever since but sort of
we've seen this
this whole um journey for ethereum and i
คิดว่าเราสามารถเรียนรู้ได้เหมือนpolka dot
ชุมชนเราสามารถเรียนรู้ได้มากมายจากสิ่งนั้น
ฉันคิดว่าสิ่งที่เราเรียนรู้ได้จากมัน
และที่ใดที่เราจะแน่ใจได้ว่าเราไม่ทำ
โดยใช้เวลานาน
ยาวและช้าเหมือนขึ้นเฟสก่อน
ถ้าคุณได้ไม้ฮอกกี้ถูกต้อง
เอ่อคือเรามั่นใจว่าเราทำได้จริงๆ
สร้างมาตรฐานให้กับบางสิ่งและ
จริง ๆ แล้วร่วมมือกันตั้งแต่แรกเริ่ม
เพราะนั่นคือสิ่งที่
โครงการ
ที่ฉันกำหนดทฤษฎีบทได้กำไรมหาศาล
ใช่ไหม
แล้วเราก็มองดู อืม
การพัฒนาอื่น ๆ เหล่านี้ทั้งหมดที่
ethereum ที่เกิดขึ้นจะมีแบบนี้
ส่วนมากของ
ชิ้นส่วนที่จำเป็นได้ถูกสร้างแล้ว
นั่น
แค่ไม่มีอยู่เหมือนใช้เวลานานเท่าไหร่
ในการใช้งาน stablecoin เหรียญแรก
ครั้งที่สองใช้เวลานานเท่าไหร่
อืมม ครั้งแรกนานแค่ไหน
ในการเริ่มใช้งาน
และอย่างที่เราเริ่มด้วย เช่น a
การเริ่มต้นที่ใหญ่เริม่ต้นที่นี่และดังนั้นฉัน
คิดว่า
ที่สามารถเป็นสิ่งที่เรามุ่งเน้น
และการบูตสแตรปของระบบนิเวศนี้
ใช่ ใช่ ฉันเห็นด้วยอย่างยิ่งว่า
ethereum มี
ปูทางไปสู่ระบบนิเวศ dfi อื่นๆ
ชนิดของการสร้าง
ชิ้นส่วนโครงสร้างพื้นฐานที่สำคัญ um
แล้วทุกคนก็สามารถเรียนรู้จากสิ่งนั้นได้
และปรับปรุงอย่างมีความหวัง
อืมมีบางอย่างเช่น a
ใกล้มาตรฐานโทเค็น c20 บนpolka dot
หรือ
หรือยังไม่เหมือนมาตรฐานโทเค็น
ฉันคิดว่าเอ่อนี่ไม่เท่ากับ
เพราะมันเหมือนชารอนคุยกับ
เฉิน แต่มีเหมือน
กลุ่มชุมชนกำลังทำงาน
ต่อสิ่งที่เหมือนโทเค็น um
ฉันจะไม่เรียกมันว่าโทเค็น
มาตรฐานมันคือการ
ถ่ายโอนมูลค่าทวีคูณผ่านเชนที่แตกต่างกัน
เอ่อ แน่นอน
ต่างเครือข่าย โอเค น่าสนใจสุดๆ
อืม
โอเค เราต้องสรุปแล้ว ดังนั้นฉัน
สามารถแชทกับผู้ก่อตั้งคนอื่นได้
อืม แต่น่าสนใจมาก อืม
ฉันจะคอยติดตามสิ่งที่พวกคุณ
รู้สึกและใช่ แล้วฉันจะปกปิดมันไว้
ที่กำหนดไว้เช่นกันดังนั้น
ขอบคุณมากเชิญเรา
วันนี้
ขอบคุณ
อืม โอเค เยี่ยมมาก ต่อไปของเราต่อไป
เกี่ยวกับ แผงหน้าปัด
อืมใช่เรามี ดีเร็กจาก
moonbeam อืม alexei จาก
interlay เอ่อ นั่นแหละ นั่นแหละ
ใช่
โซตา จาก plasm
และอืมแฮงจากฟาลาอุมซุปเปอร์
น่าสนใจมาก
การนำเสนอทั้งหมดของคุณอีกครั้งเหมือน
เหลือเชื่อจริงๆ
อืมการก่อสร้างและการพัฒนาทั้งหมด
ที่เกิดขึ้น
บน polka dotตื่นเต้นมากที่ได้เห็น
ทุกอย่างดำเนินไป
ดังนั้นฉันจะเริ่มต้นด้วยคำถามเดียวกัน ฉัน
ทำเพื่อ
แผง panel ก่อนหน้า อืม และ
ใช่ ประเภทของของคุณแต่ละคน
ขั้นตอนการพัฒนา
are you and do you expect to be live as
soon as the
proteins are the protein auction happens
um derek do you want to start sure thing
yeah so um
uh you know i i would say that uh
largely similar to some of the responses
you got from the previous
panelists you know where we are you know
working hard to be kind of ready to go
uh when the parrot chain auctions start
i think um
you know it was also mentioned that uh
um you know it's you know i know parity
has this policy of conducts ready when
it's ready so um
you know that always takes a little bit
of creative juggling to you know kind of
plan around
um but uh you know uh we see kind of a
ton of great progress happening
um you know on the development side and
in particular i think that the key area
for us is this development
of cumulus and um you know making sure
that
it has all the features uh and stability
that are needed
uh to launch and you know i anticipate
that happening
uh you know uh you know relatively soon
and you know we want to be among you
know ready to go among the first pair of
chains um
you know as those auction store okay
um alexa sure
i mean i think we're all in the same
boat um i mean as for insulin pokebit
you see
we just launched a beta test net that's
kind of the system being feature ready
from now on it's tweaks improvements on
the ux and
plus testing making sure it's robust um
but we'll be ready to go whenever kusama
and polkadot launch so from now on it's
just making sure the system's robust
that we keep improving and adding
integrations
okay cool sorry for moonbeam there's
also a beta that people can start
uh building on now right oh sure we've
had a you know a test net since
september basically like where
we have teams like sushi who you heard
from before and other you know many
other teams are deploying
uh you know deploying their applications
to it yeah perfect all right okay so
um so yep um i can go next
so i think before talking about summer
network and polkadot network uh we have
to
make lococo network stable so
they are auto program on the local
testnet so
we're gonna do our best to serve them
with party technologies and website
recommendations
and if i understand correctly the common
with the power chain will be connected
first
so probably program btc will be
connected first or something like that
then the projection will be happening so
yeah what we have to do is to make
rococo stable
with the foundation quality technologies
and all the community members
okay um okay so still some development
before you're you're ready you're ready
to go okay
um okay and then finally hang
on right yeah in the past we have spent
a lot of time like designing the
token economy to uh be compatible with
the
slot auction so actually this is the
most
complicated part i think in terms of the
i mean compared with the technology
maybe the economy
is even more complicated but of course
in terms of the technology uh i think
there are still something we need to
prepare
and as at the same time i think uh
parity is still is still working very
hard
to fill the last last few things
so for example like the stability so
written
recently we're experiencing experiencing
some
uh small problems so maybe in the next
week or so local could be reset and then
i think it will be much better and we
already seen
in this iteration is already much better
than the first uh
logo covey one now it's the second
generation logo kobe one
yeah and of course another thing is
related to the
performance and actually i think this is
uh
especially important for us uh in the
last
months we didn't test that it's just a
standalone
uh substrate blockchain and uh
in the testnet because our uh special uh
uh topology and and and the design
we have uh like more than two million
transactions
per uh in that month so it means that
if we switch to a power chain uh
and i i i expect it will have some
influence
in terms of in terms of the performance
yeah and
uh the the last one i think is the
accessibility now
i i think uh it's almost the the per
chance
architecture is almost ready but we
still cannot access the data from the
relation but and and this is already
planned and i think it will be very
important for us to build a fully
decentralized
like the incentive for the slot auction
is it will take use of this feature
yeah okay um
so okay so you you all are building uh
are part of the infrastructure to enable
different dabs uh to come
live on on polka dot um so
just stepping back a little bit
why should developers be building on
polka dot in the first place like what
are the advantages
that uh this um this
uh chain and i guess ecosystem of of
chains
provides that other other layer ones
don't
i can jump in on that um for some first
thoughts that uh
i mean i think what we're seeing is um
you know obviously
almost all the existing activities on
ethereum so that's kind of
where most of the existing developer
activity is uh but there's definitely
kind of a push and a pull going on right
so the
the push as was mentioned you know by
some of the previous panelists is
you know 100 transaction fees 300 you
know d5 fees that
i think makes people open-minded because
there's certainly some users and use
cases that
are difficult to serve in that in that
setting but the pull
is that you know i think people are
interested you know we're finding people
to be quite interested in polka dot
right i mean there's i think outside of
ethereum it's
you know it's definitely the place that
has the most organic kind of developer
activity going on like the
you know i'll call it the richest kind
of ecosystem so you know
particularly a lot of the people we're
working with um you know they want to be
a first mover in this new and growing
ecosystem they want
to you know be able to service all these
assets that are being created in this
new ecosystem so i think
that's the the pull part that it's you
know is just as powerful
that's causing you know causing uh you
know people to kind of shift over to be
looking very carefully to figure out
figuring out their deployment plans um
that's interesting because i i think the
like the
common argument for ethereum is it's
community
but you're saying that pogo that is
creating its own kind of
organic native community that is
is also becoming kind of a moat for it
i mean for my i mean maybe i'm a little
biased because i'm not obviously in it
but
i mean i would say that uh it certainly
has this kind of organic
it has an ethereum-like feel i think in
the sense that there's a lot of organic
teams you know there's a lot of like
it's not just kind of corporate it's
like nights and weekends people that are
just kind of
building because they want to because
it's fun i mean this is the kind of
things that
i think you don't see in a lot of other
layer ones
cool um um i like say doing that
sure i mean i think i think like that
summarizes up pretty well
um from my like from from i've been
doing a lot of research in this space
for for some time now and i do think
like the community on ethereum has been
growing very fast and but it also had
its start right you have to start
somewhere and what i do see like working
with polka dot is
that the community is growing very
quickly and i think that there's been a
lot of effort to get people involved
to make it understandable and actually
get people interested in the projects
i mean and i mean from our personal
experience i mean we were super
surprised i mean we've had like
i think nearly eight and a half thousand
people running our test net over like
two and a half days i mean
it's quite amazing that people actually
are willing to go download like tech get
tested bitcoin and actually try them out
on polka dots
um on testnet and i think that kind of
speaks for itself so
i do think that the community is super
strong um
it's taking a step back and looking at
the general outlook i think
like if you look at the market right now
i mean obviously ethereum fees are super
high we've seen this before
um but now you have alternatives right i
mean you've seen what binance has been
doing
very successfully in fact with pancake
swap and alternatives
um and then we have solana kind of also
moving into the game with their own emm
um but these chains i guess don't offer
you the same community and also like
decentralization benefits
so my feeling is that there is this
moment right now
and it's not going to last forever when
polkadot can actually deploy and move
into the system
and it will actually be able to gain a
lot of traction
but the moment obviously it's not going
to last forever so i do think that
we have a limited amount of time to get
everything running get the users
um onto the system and show that it
actually works and that it can compete
um with centralized platforms perhaps
even
so it's interesting that right now i
think
we are at a very kind of
special and con like a conductive moment
into ethereum alternatives launching
uh because of how high uh the fees are
there and
um you know it's it's like it's
so many people are using ethereum that
it's become unusable for
uh at least part of of users
so in that sense it seems like the the
right moment for
for ethereum alternatives to to launch
um
but uh but polka dot is still kind of
almost there but but not yet so how do
you guys
uh kind of manage that like how how do
you
um kind of take advantage of this moment
without being able to go actually live
it must be must be a little bit
frustrating
uh so i don't know
this is tough question but um
you know the one of the great things of
being community is the legit project
connected each other so i know derek and
the alexay and ham
for a while more than i think one or two
years so
yeah um so ecosystem is still too small
to compete
so we can bigger we can make it bigger
together
and the if i i would like to
make polka dot much much bigger the
ecosystem much much bigger with the
community
members as well as with foundation and
party technologies
so the good thing is we are still early
stage so we can 100
focus on technology rather than stupid
marketing stuff
so this is our advantage i think and the
technology make difference in the long
run so that's why we should focus on the
technology
and the yeah uh polkadot has
obviously advancing technology so we
would like to catch up and we will drive
to make it better
and better together i don't know i i
answered the question but um
yeah this is my comments yeah no totally
um hi do you have something to add about
any of the two
previous questions yeah uh
can you hear i see it's uh okay okay
yeah so uh actually i think uh polka dot
is quite different from other projects
like the other project is it's more like
we want to make a platform and want
everyone to move
into this platform and this is it's it's
it's may not be a good uh uh
description but to me i think it's like
a
app store or play store so they want to
build a barrier
and and i don't like this feeling and
polka dot is
completely completely different because
uh the team's building on polka dot is
perfect
and we can connect with each other and
we offer our own capability to other
blockchains
and i think the interoperability is the
core
of uh polka dot ecosystem and at the
same time i think
this is the uh this is
the the only uh unique
uh feature offered by polka dot so uh to
me i
i think this is also the the biggest
reason we want to build on polka dot
rather than other protocols yeah so i i
think uh
so far although power change is not
launched
and we have uh actually we have more
time to develop
focus on the on the development just as
i said by sota
but i i expect once polka dot is
launched
it will be huge because we can do a lot
of things
that has never it was never possible in
the
in the in the past can you go
deeper on that like and same question
goes for for everyone else
what are some of the things that you
expect uh to build on polka dot that
just weren't possible before
on other chains yeah um
i think the one of the most interesting
use case will be
dex decentralized expansion so let's say
if i developed x on the top of e syria
we can
you know exchange not only erc20 token
and these
so if you develop you know decks on the
top of alcohol
since a lot of blockchain will be
connected we can
we can exchange bitcoin to ethereum
virgin is talking to passion
tokens so um you know so this is gonna
be huge
i think this is you know very easy
use case on the top of all that
i'll chime in here that you know it's a
little bit of a riff on one of the ideas
that came up earlier that um you know
kind of the why
you know what is it that's different
about polka dot and you know i think
community is part of it but you know
there's this kind of i've been thinking
about this lately there's this
uh this idea um called conway's law
right that there's this kind of
connection between
the structure of the architecture of
software and the organization
that like use it or build it and this is
something i think is quite unique about
polkadot where
i mean every blockchain you know you're
kind of creating this community and you
get this emergent phenomenon of
something that emerges that's
kind of greater than some of its parts
but you know in poconos almost like the
super structure right i've seen i've
heard people say it's a layer zero or
it's you know they're using this
different terminology it's a little bit
hard to understand but it is kind of
this idea where
each of us here on the screen each have
our own project that are doing that
but then we're all kind of together then
building some like larger thing right it
feels like you're part of something
larger
so i do think that that's something
that's you know that is
is unique here and um that's like one of
the powerful ideas that i think
helps organize like the community you
know in a way that
is different it's like the structure of
the software lends itself to this
organization of the community
in a way that maybe isn't the case with
other platforms
yeah i think that's that's always the
case when when just
starting something out and being there
first i think it's it
must be super exciting for uh adapt
developers
um alex i don't know if you had
something said about the previous
questions
sure i mean i guess like i mean it's a
tough question right
like what makes polka dots special what
can we build we cannot build on a few
other chains and
i mean i think it's it's it's a tough
one and i think also it's probably not
exactly the question we should be asking
ourselves um
it's not about the applications but on
the technological side
it's like the main benefit of polkadot
is that you can customize your execution
now we can we'll be able to build the
same applications like dexa is like on
ethereum and
um i mean emm is definitely a zero to
one invention but
i mean potentially you cannot move
towards more
traditional um models which have less
problems like avoid the permanent loss
for example or even
manage to build some form of order book
system on top of polka
but then again it's it's it's a very
tough question to answer and predict um
what we can see right now for example is
that when building new applications
you have much more flexibility i mean
from our example we were able to build
an on-chain key derivation mechanism
um to derive um bitcoin addresses
essentially what your wallets typically
would do off chain on polkadot on chain
this is impossible on ethereum the costs
of doing optical operations
on the vm are way too high and you kill
the application
but we can now actually say okay we're
not going to optimize
each line of code at the cost of
usability we can actually
make sure that the users have a better
experience and still not
actually like slow down the entire
system and make the application unusable
because the performance bottlenecks so i
think
that's at the moment i think the largest
benefit you can customize what you're
building you can optimize for the
specific thing that you want
rather than having to work with this
universal toolkit which i think
like dvm is is a brilliant thing that we
had and we still have i mean a lot of
projects
are deploying evms on top of their power
chains because it is so easy for
developers to get it
to actually to build on the system but
if you want to dig in deeper if you
actually want to build something more
complex
i think that's when you actually will
want to go for power chain and then of
course you have the argument for rust
and wasm over
um solidity and the vm in the long term
but
that's that's i think a bet people will
have to take right
yeah so there's a kind of the
um over lying
over like the broad theme um i've heard
today is
how specialization will will win in the
end
and people will want kind of these um
more uh
these kind of blockchains that you can
modify to your own
projects uh features and and needs so
um yeah definitely will be interesting
to see how that develops and
let's say i just had a specific question
on on the bitcoin
uh bridge because i think kind of the
the main um issue with these bridges are
how they need to trust um
uh who who is controlling the assets in
the bridge
so just wanted to to clarify that with
interlake how
uh what what level of control does the
team have over
uh the assets being held on the bridge
on like bitcoin being transferred to the
bridge
but we don't have any control at all um
so like exclaim is a is a paper that we
released in 2018 it's actually been peer
reviewed and accepted at a
conference and the main contribution was
that anyone can run only one of these
vaults if they put down collateral
so users have to guarantee that if
someone misbehaves they'll get
at least they will kind of have some
financial guarantees that they won't
lose
from the economic perspective in chile
as a team okay we might run one of these
vaults but so can anybody else there is
no restrictions you don't have to buy
any tokens to participate
and as for the perch in itself it will
be running under polka dots governance
mechanics
um i can't say too much at this stage
but we are going for one
we are actually looking to make this a
system that's available for common good
without going into more detail there
so intelli won't have full control over
this and it's that's not our vision and
we don't want to have control over it
so that year is to have a decentralized
from the start
and what i can say like we will never be
able to steal any uses funds and we
never want to be able
even to like even tell the possibility
of doing that
okay so anyone can can control vaults
and one what's the incentive for
controlling vaults
so right now basically i mean you earn
um fees of the total volume
that goes to the power chain and then
there will be models
for additional incentives for vaults in
collaboration with polka dots
plus of course taking derivatives are a
very interesting aspect
aspect that we're exploring at the
moment um so you will look so
essentially what's going to most likely
happen is you'll be able to reuse the
collateral that you put down as a vault
either freely change taking for
parachuting auctions or other
mechanisms and you'll essentially have
exposure to different apis so the
additive
you contribute to the polka dots and
also poke ability at the same time
okay so so people can stake right now
so i mean right now you can run a vault
you can it's on beta volts are open
source you can go and register the vault
request dot test and dot from from the
faucet and you're good to go
i mean of course it's still in beta so
it's all it doesn't have economic value
um but we're really looking forward to
getting this um
up to speed on christmas as well
and then i had a specific question on on
fala too the
privacy network um i think i i got kind
of a little bit lost in
in the presentation and was wondering
for the user
um to to have uh like private
transactions and
interactions with different different
apps is having a
uh fala based wallet uh
basically what what like the the thing
that you need
to have private transactions or is there
an additional step
that you need to do yeah uh of course
there are there are
some problems if you don't have a
special
kind of wallet because like if you uh
interact with some uh powertrain
directly
you you write creators transactions sign
it
and and broadcast it to the person and
that's all
but for us uh because we want to
maintain the confidentiality
so at least before you submit something
to our blockchain you need to encrypt it
and before you encrypt it you need a you
need a key
right so the key is uh it is made
from some key uh uh key agreement
uh protocol between the user between the
end user and the secure enclave
so uh in this uh uh if in this
perspective
and that the answer is yes so uh
if any protocol wants to interact with
us
at least uh their user side will need to
integrate with our sdk
but uh uh we have two ways to
uh to inter interact with the different
power change uh the one way is like you
can use
xcm to send some message but maybe the
content of the message is already
end to end encrypted and it is done by
some sdk
in like user's wallet or browser another
way is that
if uh some some data is already on file
a network
and user can interact with fellow
network direct
directly so in this way actually they
talk to the secure enclave
rather than the our blockchain we
separate the consensus and the
computation
so uh everything happens off the
blockchain
and it can make the performance even
better
okay got it and then um questions for
for sota and and derek um
so you're you're providing uh like
platforms for for adapts to
to build uh on on polka dot and you
already have like some
already some uh some teams building
there
so uh curious what
what are the next uh projects
either like whether they're ethereum
based or or new projects
that you are seeing uh coming to your
your
your platforms like what do you think
will be the first steps to come live on
polka dot
whoever soda do you want to go first go
ahead yeah um
so i think this is great question in the
actually the yeah while the frequently
asked
question from investor is what is the
difference from between movie and
problem so
yeah but uh ecosystem is still too small
to compete so we can be gathered
together
so yeah i respect what derek is doing
in that system and the yeah in terms of
the collaboration and the announcement
we decided not to announce the
partnership and the collaboration
without code
without demo and without you know movp
minimum valuable product and the we have
a you know some upcoming collaboration
and partnership
and the yes some yeah some project i
i don't want to disclose some of the
project but one project i can describe
with microsoft so we are talking with
microsoft
japan and it will be disclosed very soon
and what what's microsoft doing yeah
they are providing infrastructure for
the plaza network
in the they're yeah we are doing
together to make the
the the node service then anyone can
deploy body data on the top of the
network
this is not a task but uh right you know
important function
in the community oh interesting okay
um so okay so you work with microsoft
for microsoft to
help run the uh
you set the notes on by by using azure
okay and any depth you can disclose or
or i guess like sectors like
i don't know you can say like a lending
protocol yeah
okay so secret
all right okay um derek
and by the way like super interesting to
see um sushi swap
and balance are already uh building on
on moon beams
so what what else can we expect yeah i
mean i'll just
uh you know there's a lot of individual
projects but if i just uh talk broadly i
would say that you know it's certainly
the case that
d5 like the d5 sector is like where we
we found the most
traction and just to step back i mean
our strategy is basically to
approach ethereum based projects um as
natural partners because
given our ethereum compatible approach
you know there's kind of minimal change
needed on their end to be able to
deploy the moon beam and then in doing
so have a pokedex deployment
but certainly defy i'd say they're the
most uh aggressive to adopt i think
and one of the reasons i think is that
they
you know when it comes to these ux you
know kind of concerns that alexa was
talking about i feel like a lot of the
d5 people actually
don't care as much about that uh their
users are like power users and
you know they can be pretty big
obstacles and people kind of like plow
through right you know
i think that uh that's kind of like you
know they're they're definitely like um
you know they're the place where we got
the first option although i will say
that i'm pretty bullish on
uh the nft sector as well so i think
that this same kind of dynamic we talked
about before
is certainly affecting you know nft
based projects on ethereum where you
know you have a hundred dollar
transaction fee what does that mean for
nft assets that cost less than a hundred
dollars i mean they're right they're a
little bit stranded so
i think that you know and what one
pattern that we've seen is that
you know minimum people want you know to
potentially have multiple
back ends where they can mint these
things and then you even offer the user
a choice right to say well where do you
want to create this thing and maybe
there's some trade-offs to be considered
like you know it's expensive on ethereum
but maybe
you know there's more potential you know
buyers and other nft compatible systems
or but maybe you want
uh you know uh for a less expensive one
it makes more sense to go to a place
where it's going to be cheaper to mint
and obviously you know that may make
sense for other use cases
yeah and here um i would like to talk
about nfc as well
so uh luckily i'm japanese even though
i'm in singapore so
uh you know we have a lot of content
such as manga anime
and so we are talking with our auto nft
project in japan
in these they are interested in the
polkadot system
to to deploy anything in this case
i think yeah like manga and nfts make it
are like a dream combination
yeah yeah i think so yeah it will be
cool to see that on on pokedot
um so uh we are running out of time i
actually have to jump on something else
that like
in five minutes so um i want to
ask you a similar question to
the the the last final just your longer
term vision
for uh for polka dot either you know
defy on polka dot or just
web 3 on on polka dot um where do you
see it
uh by the end of the year and where do
you see it just
you know 10 years from now
i'll jump in i throw my head in the ring
to start um i mean
i think you know right now you know
we're just seeing kind of this like
straight
porting action at least that's what
we're seeing right so someone has an app
it's fully working on ethereum they'd
want to just port the whole thing
you know to you know to something like
moonbeam or possum
uh even so um that's kind of what i
still consider to be a little bit like
you know generation one you know kind of
kind of architecture i mean
the thing i'm probably most excited
about on polka dot comes from this like
specialized you know specialized
infrastructural
chains right so i anticipate that
there's going to be
multi-chain based applications um you
know that will use different
specialized services just natively on
polka dot and i think that's gonna you
know those are gonna be the kind of apps
that will really take advantage of
you know this ability to have these like
specialized like different services
i think that's still you know relatively
early and there's obviously these very
well trodden kind of existing patterns
that people are already used to but
you know that's kind of what i see um
you know that that's kind of what i see
like moving forward that is
i'm most excited about i'd say cool
um alex you want to go um well i guess i
mean
end of the year will be live i mean
that's definitely
i mean yeah there is no other there's an
alternative let's put it this way
um and in 10 years i mean i think like i
i
probably put my bet on poco essentially
being this
multi-chain infrastructure where you
have specialized chains and different
applications
um where it's moving away from this
generalized kind of
contract layers we'll have more and more
people and more applications coming in
building very dedicated services for
example dexes which focus on the low
level
basically optimize for high frequency
trading and make sure that they
um can actually squeeze out the last bit
out of like this execution models
yeah and yeah yeah yeah um i can go next
so i think um we have a very important
role in the ecosystem
in the actually i don't know the future
we do not predict the future we make the
future
so we're gonna do our best to realize
level 3.0 together with our ecosystem
member
sorry for the answer i
love it i i think uh in the in
like in the uh in the late this year i
think d5 will also
will still be the i think the most
valuable
uh use cases on polka dots as well as
the other blockchains
but in the long run i think in like 10
years of course defy
uh it's it targets the very high
value users and very high value uh use
cases
but because of i i think because of
uh the good architecture uh provided by
polkadot and we can extend to
multiple blockchains and it makes us
it makes it possible to do computations
on the blockchain and it
maybe in the future will make it
possible to store
a big large amount of file
uh in some kinds of uh decentralized
network so if we combine them together
it means
that maybe in the future the cloud
computing will be fully decentralized
and i think
this is uh i think it will be
the next huge thing for blockchain yeah
and
this is how well this is the original
version
vision of web3 very cool
okay so a decentralized feature an
interconnected future
a specialized feature and i i'm going to
put that on a t-shirt we don't predict
the future we make it
so very nice all right um so
interesting chatting with all of you and
um thanks for
for inviting me um ashley
if you're somewhere there um to moderate
i i had a blast
so hi everyone